<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/prayer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:34:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/maralkan-logo-favicon-3.png</url>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Letter to God</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/">Letter to God</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-390"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace. And be thankful. Let the message of Christ dwell among you richly as you teach and admonish one another with all wisdom through psalms, hymns, and songs from the Spirit, singing to God with gratitude in your hearts. And whatever you do, whether in word or deed, do it all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. — Colossians 3:15-17</p></blockquote>
<p>We were charged to write a letter to God in order to connect with God at a more personal level and to be more grateful for what He has done in our lives. As grateful followers/disciples, we can go out and actually evangelize this world. Gratitude is something that I&#8217;ve noticed brings a lot of repentance and change in people. No matter where they come from.</p>
<p>I include my letter here.</p>
<p>Dear Dad,</p>
<p>I am very glad that I can talk to you this morning. Thank you for the privilege of being able to write this letter to you. Thank you God for always being there to bring in a new day. You keep the stars in their current trajectories. You keep the sun in it&#8217;s place. You allow the Earth to continue rotating on it&#8217;s axis at the particular angle that it is tilted at. You stand at eternity radiating peace, love, patience, kindness, joy.</p>
<p>I am nothing like you God. And yet you cared enough to make man in your image. Something that we, as your creations, are unable to do. We cannot create another person from scratch. And if we do, it&#8217;s with your materials. We can&#8217;t create our atoms from scratch. We can&#8217;t do anything without you, God.</p>
<p>I was listening to some songs where the singer expresses lots of gratitude towards their best friend. And these are people who don&#8217;t really know you, God! How can I say that I&#8217;ve been grateful to you? Please forgive me for being so ungrateful to you. I haven&#8217;t even stopped to think about how much you&#8217;ve done for me for quite a while, now. Thank you God for always being there for me. You were there when I was burned and in the hospital. When I cried out in prayer and the nurses and doctors were telling my mom to shut me up. And yet they witnessed a miracle in front of their eyes. I should not even be alive if it weren&#8217;t for you. Yet again, when I&#8217;ve been in danger multiple times in my life. Running in the streets of Downtown Oakland in the night, fearing that I would be jumped or taken hostage by someone. When you protected me from many more things. I&#8217;ve had my life placed in so many dangerous situations and yet I continue to live. Thank you God for not giving up on me.</p>
<p>There have been times when I trust people more than I trusted you. Primarily, it was before I was a disciple. But even as a disciple, I&#8217;ve placed my trust in people. When it was revealed, I was broken and realized that it was you that I needed, not the love of someone else. I was trying to be in a situation where I felt loved by someone here on earth. But then I realized that I&#8217;m not trying to store up treasures for myself here on earth. Why was I trying to do that? I didn&#8217;t trust you, God. But I realize now that you were always there.</p>
<p>You were there when I felt so discouraged and lonely in Berkeley. I have a feeling you were probably whispering in my ear, telling me to seek after you. To not follow through with the desires to end it all. I didn&#8217;t end it all. I ended up at the TSF. Although it wasn&#8217;t the right place to be at, it was the right place at the right time. You set up the times and places for everyone. For my family. For myself. You are the one who made it all possible. You kept me alive. You allowed me to experience the world as I did. I was betrayed, trusted, betrayed again. And I saw the hearts of people turn away from me. And yet I didn&#8217;t learn my lesson. I didn&#8217;t understand that I was still trusting in men. Even for a while as a disciple, I still felt led by people and not by you. But you were still there. You were faithful even though I was not.</p>
<p>You also gave me the family that I have today. They love me. And there are times when I am ungrateful towards them. I yell at them, letting them know that I&#8217;m a person as well (at least, in my mind). I thought that by yelling at them I would stop them from yelling at me. (haha I was so wrong). When I thought that they were against me because they did not let me do the Academic Decathlon, I was extremely rebellious. And yet, you allowed that to happen. You allowed me to go to Sam K. and let him know that he&#8217;s better than my parents. I sincerely thought he was looking out for me more than my own parents were. I still have confusion about that. I don&#8217;t understand what my parents motives were. I don&#8217;t understand Sam&#8217;s motivations. All I know is that my motivations were selfish. I had an intense selfish ambition. I wanted to feel honored and respected by everyone else. I wanted to hear that I was better than someone else. And I was very disappointed when I didn&#8217;t get it. And God, you obviously had a hand in that. My strong suit was supposed to be math. And I was failing at it. I understood how to do it. But, in practice, I couldn&#8217;t do it under pressure.</p>
<p>You gave me talent. There are many times that I&#8217;m afraid of saying that I can do things because I don&#8217;t want to be prideful. And by feeling that, I feel insecure. I want to be called humble. So paradoxical&#8230; and yet again, signs of pride. I really have nothing to bring to the table but the things that you&#8217;ve given me. I only ask that you allow me to use these talents to glorify you. Allow me to reach out with this. I can reach a community that is not often reached. I have access to some of the greatest minds, according to the wisdom of the world. And yet, I can sometimes let it slip. I feel lazy. I don&#8217;t feel like studying. I don&#8217;t feel like trying to glorify you. But you are still there.</p>
<p>Dad, you made me to glorify you and do your work. Thank you for giving me a new purpose for my life. Thank you for giving me friends who care. Thank you for allowing me to be in your kingdom. Thank you for allowing me to come clean to you. Thank you for your forgiveness.</p>
<p>Thank you, Jesus for your sacrifice. Thank you that because you denied yourself, I don&#8217;t have to suffer for eternity. Thank you that you&#8217;ve given me eyesight, hearing, language, normalcy in brain habit. Thank you for giving me the brothers and sister that I have. Thank you for testing my faith, that it may be refined by fire. Thank you for placing me in charge of websites. Thank you for placing me under Jeff and Jovanny. Thank you for teaching me your words. Thank you for answering my prayers with getting to know you. Thank you for bringing in so many souls. Thank you for my brothers and sisters around the world. Thank you for your love. Thank you for everything. Thank you for the job that I have. Thank you for allowing me to share with my co-workers alongside a fellow brother and disciple. Thank you for giving me clothing to wear. Thank you for giving me good to eat. Thank you for giving me a new computer. Thank you for giving me what I need. Thank you for giving me people to lead. I&#8217;m unworthy of receiving anything. I&#8217;m like the prodigal son. I don&#8217;t deserve it. I&#8217;m like the other soon, feeling like I deserve something that I really don&#8217;t. Thank you God.</p>
<p>You are awesome in everything that you do. You are incredible. You work great miracles in our day and age. You are patient, kind, loving, generous, faithful.</p>
<p>You gave it all for me. Why can&#8217;t I give it all to you? God, give me strength to carry on your dream. Give me strength to do your will when I cannot. All things come from you. All things are made by you.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s so much more that I can pray about as well. Brothers and sisters around the world are struggling. Some are sick some are not. People in this world are suffering because of sin. Help them get closer to you. Give them what they need to seek you. For the workers in the harvest. Lord send me. Here I am Lord. Send me.</p>
<p>I very well would like to go to Japan. I would very much like to share with souls who need saving from their destructive worldview. Sometimes it&#8217;s mind boggling to me to see that people want yo believe in ghosts and not in you. People want yo believe in death, in demons, in statues, in money. People understand these things at the intellectual level but do not practice them. I saw that at bible talk. A woman tried to defend her independence from you. I could hear pride come out.</p>
<p>Thanks for all that you do!</p>
<p>-Your son,<br />
Marvin Alcántara</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/">Letter to God</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
