<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>5 Million Dollar Jackpot &#8211; Million Dollar Mindset &#8211; Proforma</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/5-million-dollar-jackpot-million-dollar-mindset-proforma/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/5-million-dollar-jackpot-million-dollar-mindset-proforma/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/?p=886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_887" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-887" style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class="size-full wp-image-887" src="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/5-Million-Dollar-Jackpot.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="628" srcset="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/5-Million-Dollar-Jackpot.jpg 1200w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/5-Million-Dollar-Jackpot-300x157.jpg 300w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/5-Million-Dollar-Jackpot-1024x536.jpg 1024w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/5-Million-Dollar-Jackpot-768x402.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-887" class="wp-caption-text">5 Million Dollar Jackpot &#8211; Million Dollar Mindset &#8211; Greg Muzzillo Blog<br />This was made for the Million Dollar Mindset blog by Greg Muzzillo, the founder of Proforma.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/5-million-dollar-jackpot-million-dollar-mindset-proforma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Victory &#8211; YouTube Thumbnail for Sermon &#8211; TBICC</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/victory-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/victory-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/?p=883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_884" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-884" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-884" src="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-victory.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="450" srcset="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-victory.jpeg 800w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-victory-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-victory-768x432.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-884" class="wp-caption-text">Victory &#8211; YouTube Thumbnail for Sermon<br />This is a YouTube thumbnail created for a sermon that was uploaded to YouTube by the same title.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/victory-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day After Day &#8211; YouTube Thumbnail for Sermon &#8211; TBICC</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/day-after-day-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/day-after-day-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/?p=880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_881" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-881" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-881" src="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-day_after_day.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="450" srcset="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-day_after_day.jpeg 800w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-day_after_day-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tbicc-yt_thumbnail-day_after_day-768x432.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-881" class="wp-caption-text">Day After Day &#8211; YouTube Thumbnail for Sermon<br />This is a YouTube thumbnail created for a sermon that was uploaded to YouTube by the same title.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/day-after-day-youtube-thumbnail-for-sermon-tbicc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spiritual Blindness YT Thumbnail &#8211; TBICC</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/spiritual-blindness-yt-thumbnail-tbicc/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/spiritual-blindness-yt-thumbnail-tbicc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/?p=877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_878" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-878" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-878" src="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/spiritual_blindness-yt_thumbnail-tbicc.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="450" srcset="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/spiritual_blindness-yt_thumbnail-tbicc.jpeg 800w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/spiritual_blindness-yt_thumbnail-tbicc-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/spiritual_blindness-yt_thumbnail-tbicc-768x432.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-878" class="wp-caption-text">Spiritual Blindness &#8211; YouTube Thumbnail for Sermon<br />This is a YouTube thumbnail created for a sermon that was uploaded to YouTube by the same title.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/spiritual-blindness-yt-thumbnail-tbicc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Service at the Park &#8211; TBICC</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/sunday-service-at-the-park-tbicc/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/sunday-service-at-the-park-tbicc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 05:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/?p=872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_875" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-875" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-875" src="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/park-service-tbicc.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="800" srcset="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/park-service-tbicc.jpeg 800w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/park-service-tbicc-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/park-service-tbicc-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/park-service-tbicc-768x768.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-875" class="wp-caption-text">Sunday Service at the Park Invite This was created as a flyer for a church service to be held at a local park.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/sunday-service-at-the-park-tbicc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Beetle</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexican American]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viva Mexico]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;We&#8217;re invisible to people like that, Jaime&#8221; Milagros from the Blue Beetle (2023) When I was seven years old, growing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re invisible to people like that, Jaime&#8221;</p>
<cite>Milagros from the Blue Beetle (2023)</cite></blockquote>



<p>When I was seven years old, growing up in the projects in Los Angeles, I learned about my Mexican heritage. I transferred to an elementary school that had a Magnet program (a school program that focuses kids onto a career path). This Math/Science/Tech Magnet school promised to put me onto a career path in the STEM field and promised to open doors for me that would allow me to do just that. It was at this school where I met African Americans for the first time. I distinctly remember feeling left out all the time because I had only learned to speak English two years before and I still needed ESL (English as a Second Language) classes. I learned about my Mexican heritage. I had never noticed myself as different until then. After two years there, I hated my experience. I had one friend but I was always picked on for being Mexican. I moved back to my old elementary school. I walked into my fourth grade class feeling like an outsider. My mom never allowed me to make friends with the <em>barrio</em>. I had missed out on three years with my classmates (I missed my entire first grade). I remember feeling like an outsider but it still felt like home.</p>



<p>I stayed with my classmates but the feeling never really went away. I remained an outsider because I was not allowed to cross the street to hang out with my school friends. Middle school came and I met the Asian American clicks. I found myself drifting between clicks. My closest friend was a Chinese kid. He and I got into trouble roaming the school halls during lunch (the halls were closed during lunch). I met a White kid and tried making friends with him only to be threatened by him. I didn&#8217;t realize I had met an Emo kid. This Emo White kid went on to become a dealer in powder and I stayed away from him. Despite the fact that I had one friend, I always felt alone. This feeling of loneliness pushed my one friend away and I sought another friendship. This time, I befriended a new kid on the block. I showed him where everything was and we became friends. He would come over to my place and we would play video games when my parents weren&#8217;t home. But we pushed it too far once and my parents came home early to surprise me. Needless to say, they banned him from going anywhere near me. I had no friends again.</p>



<p>I decided to go to a different high school that nobody else in my neighborhood attended. That school had a Math/Science/Tech Magnet. I went there because I hated the local bully so I just wanted to get away. At this school, I met a very diverse student body. I drifted and befriended a group of girls that everyone considered losers. I remember believing that I was, too, a loser and I could never hope to really get a pretty girl or make deep friendships.</p>



<p>I hated my parents and my Mexican heritage. They always cited our heritage as the reason why I should only make friends with my family members. I felt like they did not understand that they were hurting me. I didn&#8217;t get along with my siblings. I tried to have my parents deported out of sheer hatred. They never meant to harm me. The opposite was true. They really loved me and wanted the best for me. I was not successful (for which I am beyond grateful to God that He did not allow that to happen). They believed that I could never count on any friends I made because at the end of the day, only my family would be there for me. I hated that idea and rejected my family and my heritage. I made a concerted effort to try to speak English without a Mexican accent. I decided to learn to speak other languages because I thought it would make me not Mexican. I succeeded and I chose to go to whatever college was furthest from my family. I wanted to be something else just not Mexican. I hated the racism that my parents experienced. I hated that my family had suffered so much and they had to do it all on their own. My dad was mugged and he had to surrender ALL of our money. My mom had to carry a 100-pound bag of perfumes selling door-to-door every day for 15 hours a day just to put food on our table and say that they were on their way to the ever-elusive American Dream. My mom&#8217;s immediate family had abandoned her when she arrived in the States. They were around and would come to my birthday party. But they never lifted a finger to help my parents when we really needed it the most. My dad&#8217;s family&#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say I just met them for the first time now that I&#8217;m 29 years old. My parents taught me that family was everything but it was not true for them. So why should I love being Mexican? I also abandoned my once true faith in God. I became an atheist.</p>



<p>In college I lost myself. I got into self-destructive behavior and became depressed and gave myself over to pornography addictions because it was just better to feel that over the immensely negative perspective I had of my family. I proclaimed to my roommates that there was no God and that I only believed in myself. I was going to get out of my situation. I was determined but I had no real purpose or mission. I felt empty and I saw that everyone around me seemed oppressed by some sort of darkness in their life. Everyone was clamoring to be the very top of the class&#8230; and for what?</p>



<p>It was at this point that I contemplated suicide. I was hopeless and miserable. On the outside I smiled but I was flaking away like a very slow Thanos snap. I planned it out and decided on a day and time. I had everything ready. The hour that I was going to do it, one of my roommates, a skinny Chinese kid, burst into my dorm and asked me to go with him to Southside Berkeley to get dinner. I declined his offer and told him I was busy. But Matthew did not give up. He insisted and stood up to me. I just HAD to go with him because he felt unsafe walking through the dark part of campus. I reluctantly agreed and decided that I could postpone my self-harm behavior to help someone else. That broke my feeling of emptiness. At the end of our walk, he led me into an office space and I saw a big group of Asians that looked way too friendly for my liking. I got my Korean BBQ and sat down. It turns out he brought me to a Bible study. I was furious at him. I HATED GOD! I felt a rage that I desperately tried to calm. I didn&#8217;t know it but Matthew saved my life that day. To this day, I owe him a debt of gratitude. I calmed down and listened to the lesson. I don&#8217;t remember what the lesson was about but I distinctly remember raising my hand because I wanted to be an active participant all of a sudden. I blurted out that Jesus was my friend. I remember thinking, &#8220;Why the &#8212;- did I just say that out loud? I don&#8217;t even believe that &#8212;-.&#8221;</p>



<p>I now wanted to be an Asian. Chinese folks had always been kind to me ever since I met them. I went to every Bible study meeting because I felt comfortable. I made my first deep friendships in my life. I never wanted to let go. But my grades were slipping and my depression was still going. I was placed on Academic Probation and then I was dismissed from the University. I stayed another year with the Asian church. Until one day, one of the guys confronted me: &#8220;You should stop being prideful and go home to face the music with your family.&#8221; I was terrified because they didn&#8217;t know I had been dismissed. I hid it from my family.</p>



<p>I had to face my family and my heritage again. I didn&#8217;t want to go. But James, my confronter, was adamant that I would not be welcome to continue living with at the church household. For my own good, I needed to leave. I quit my job and moved back to Los Angeles that same week&#8230; feeling defeated and nauseous.</p>



<p>I apologized to my mom for the first time for attempting to deport her and my dad. I promised that I would change and be different. I set a boundary with my parents. I would no longer help them on Sundays with their business because I wanted to go to church. They gave me a very hard time because they said that they had just gotten me back and they weren&#8217;t going to allow this. I didn&#8217;t listen. I went to church at the Los Angeles branch of the same church. But I didn&#8217;t have the same relationships that I had built in Berkeley. I felt alone again. Worse, I tried getting in touch with the friends I had made up North and nobody texted me back or emailed me back. I felt abandoned by my friends, by my church, by my heritage, by my family, by God. I had started to believe in God (after a long back-and-forth two years with my mentors, Kevin Tan and Victor Shia).</p>



<p>I started school at East Los Angeles College (ELAC). It felt wrong because nobody here was pursuing a PhD or a Master&#8217;s degree. It felt wrong because these were ordinary people and I felt like I belonged with a different crowd. It felt wrong because the student body was primarily Mexican. But it also felt familiar and comfortable. I decided to let go of my pride and learn to love being Mexican. I got on my knees and prayed to God to show me the way to live. A few days later, a Guatemalan skater approached my table by the food truck (where I was hosting my own &#8220;God Talk&#8221;) and he asked me if I wanted to study the Bible so I can learn the way to live. I was shocked because everything he was saying was almost the exact words I prayed in my prayer in my home alone on my knees. I studied the Bible for a few weeks and became a Christian when I was baptized on March 20, 2015 in Alhambra, CA.</p>



<p>It was at this time that I embraced being Mexican for the first time. I felt free and I was so excited to come home and tell my family that I had changed my life. But I went home to a big fight and they told me to take my Christianity to the trash. I felt rejected by my family but I had found a church family that would become my best friends. The skater kid, Jeff, became my best friend. He and I watched Spanish-language movies, TV shows, went on double dates with the sisters in the church, and I met his family. They helped me see that my view of family was wrong. I was wrong about my heritage. I was wrong about my direction in life. I was wrong to believe that I was an outsider. I was wrong and I was never more excited to be wrong! I started listening to <em>mariachi</em>, <em>corridos</em>, reggaeton, cumbia, salsa. I watched <em>Betty La Fea</em> and <em>La Fea Más Bella</em> reruns. I became an expert at making <em>enchiladas</em>. I absolutely wanted to embrace everything about how God made me. I enjoyed listening to Luis Miguel with my mom and would play it on my speaker and danced with her. There was still trouble at home but I was FREE! I finally felt comfortable in my own skin.</p>



<p>I visited Mexico City for the first time ever last month and I felt at home. I was there for a church missions conference and for my seminary school graduation. But I felt a connection to my heritage that I had never felt. My extended family met us there and I was on cloud nine walking through the streets of <em>El Cuerno</em> in the <em>Delegación Álvaro Obregón</em>. I met my dad&#8217;s side of the family for the first time and learned why they never visited. They are barely making it and are struggling to survive. I felt helpless and grateful for their generous hospitality. I felt like my family had welcomed me with a warm embrace and that I would always be welcome. I visited the pyramids at the Aztec-named city of <em>Teotihuacán</em>. I visited the Huey Teocalli dig site. I fell in love with my parents&#8217; home country. I practiced my Spanish to the point where my Mexican-residing side of the family told me that I did not have an American accent. I felt proud of that and felt proud of being Mexican. Eleven years ago, I just wished that my life would end. Today, I&#8217;m grateful to Matthew Liu for saving my life for such a time as this. THANK YOU!</p>



<p>Last night, I watched the Blue Beetle movie. I felt so invigorated that I was represented on the big screen that I overlooked some of the bad acting until one of the guys pointed it out. I saw the inside of the Reyes&#8217; house and felt like it was home. I took it personal when the villains challenged the protagonist. I felt that it was an attack on my home and my heritage. I cried and laughed during the movie. I felt simple joy afterwards. I felt represented as a Mexican American. I could never be more proud of my parents for making the BOLD and BRAVE move to the States.</p>



<p>#VivaMexico #MexicanAmerican #BlueBeetle</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Priorities</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enjoy life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is the most important thing in your life?I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is the most important thing in your life?<span id="more-768"></span>I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at work. I woke up late, arrived at work late, and was clumsy in my servitude and customer service. I made my entire team struggle hard. And I was just struggling to keep up. It was only after work that I got to sit down, read my Bible, and pray. But that is one day of my life!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s crazy to think that our lives happen so quickly. We continue to strive and move forward but lately I&#8217;ve found myself wanting to stay. I wanted to retreat from the world of worry and from what causes me to stress. I felt like running away from my responsibilities and just floating on whatever. (Can anyone relate?) I just wanted to feel numb and live/work to get pleasure. But, this is a dark place! This kind of living leads to emptiness and suffering and ultimately, destructive behaviors that I was once enslaved to. And I couldn&#8217;t help but feel alone in all of it. But everyone goes through this. And I&#8217;m probably one of the best examples of how not to live life. It&#8217;s just not something that people talk about out loud.</p>
<p>Everyone knows that our lives are difficult. But, what do we make of it? Life has so much to offer! Thank God that we have a life to enjoy!</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;When times are good, be happy;<br />
but when times are bad, consider this:<br />
God has made the one<br />
as well as the other.<br />
Therefore, no one can discover<br />
anything about their future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 7:14</p></blockquote>
<p>Sure, we can have awesome days. But we all have those days that just don&#8217;t sit well with us. So I found myself reading this Scripture and found that the good and the bad, God allows. I need to learn something from everything! God is good. God is my Father. The bad can help me learn to improve my character.</p>
<p>So then, if I get caught up with all of the things in the middle of life, what then will I do? I can fill up my life with all of these fringe things that I can forget to appreciate what God has given to me.</p>
<p>I have:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kingdom of God</li>
<li>a physical family that loves me</li>
<li>great schooling</li>
<li>a decent job (it could be better, amen)</li>
</ul>
<p>As I fill my life, I must consider first, then, what is important. What is my purpose? What are my goals and dreams? What needs to come first?</p>
<p>Here are my answers:</p>
<ol>
<li>My purpose: to make disciples of all nations</li>
<li>My goal this year: to be a Bible Talk leader (a small group leader with a charge to evangelize a certain geographical region)</li>
<li>My dreams: to evangelize Japan and Mexico</li>
</ol>
<p>What is important?</p>
<ol>
<li>God (quiet times: singing to Him, praying, reading my Bible)</li>
<li>His Kingdom (spiritual family)</li>
<li>Family (physical family) &#8211;&gt; fun is included! -&gt; this is new to me</li>
<li>School</li>
<li>Work</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, on a practical level, this requires that I have a job that can finance these goals. It&#8217;s important that I never put my job over God, His Kingdom, or my family.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;So I commend the enjoyment of life, because there is nothing better for a person under the sun than to eat and drink and be glad. Then joy will accompany them in their toil all the days of the life God has given them under the sun. When I applied my mind to know wisdom and to observe the labor that is done on earth—people getting no sleep day or night—then I saw all that God has done. No one can comprehend what goes on under the sun. Despite all their efforts to search it out, no one can discover its meaning. Even if the wise claim they know, they cannot really comprehend it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 8:15-17</p></blockquote>
<p>So I will live by this: &#8220;Enjoy the lifestyle that God has set out for you&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;But everyone who hears these words of mine and does not put them into practice is like a foolish man who built his house on sand.&#8221;</p>
<p>Matthew 7:26</p></blockquote>
<p>I implore whoever reads this to also reevaluate their priorities. God is most important. It&#8217;s the most important question you can ask!</p>
<p>What is your purpose in life? Post in the comments! How do you want to change and live for God?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptable sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardened hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-699"></span></p>
<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just posting my notes.</p>
<p>The alarms aren&#8217;t sounding&#8230; God has warned his people of the consequences of their sin. Nobody listens. In fact, they shut their ears.</p>
<p>This is why the anger of God burns&#8230; They do not listen!</p>
<p>v14. To dress a wound improperly as though it were not serious is a very serious deceit. This hardening goes from the leaders to the people. If the leaders aren&#8217;t ashamed of their own conduct, the people won&#8217;t be ashamed either.&nbsp;This leads to a definitive hardening in the hearts of many.</p>
<p>v16. This is a crossroads. Every time I get discipling, it is a crossroads. I can choose to follow God&#8217;s way or my own way. God&#8217;s way: the good way, where I will find rest for my soul.</p>
<p>This is a case of discipline. When I was younger, my mom would often discipline me by threatening to make an example of me in front of my classmates. Man.. how I feared that! I feared that my deeds would be exposed. I feared that I would be exposed as some sort of incredibly immature guy. For a long time, I held on to this fear. And my mom never came through with the threats. I hardened myself to her and resisted her discipline. I&#8217;m very grateful that God did this for me. Later on, I would be disciplined by my brother in the church and, initially, I resisted and didn&#8217;t understand what was going on. And all that pains me now is that anyone with a hardened heart cannot please God. I couldn&#8217;t please my mom because I had started to dislike her and her discipline.</p>
<p>v20. Sacrifices that are fancy, much labor, or even great sacrifices aren&#8217;t pleasing to God and are, in fact, worship in vain when my heart is hard.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lord says:&nbsp;&#8220;These people come near to me with their mouth and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me.&nbsp;Their worship of me is based on merely human rules they have been taught&#8230;&#8221;&nbsp;— Isaiah 29:13 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>These sacrifices aren&#8217;t even acceptable!</p>
<p>v22. God will bring discipline! God warned his people and then disaster struck.</p>
<p>v26.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Suddenly the destroyer will come upon us.&#8221;&nbsp;— Jeremiah 6:26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>And this is the hand of God, not Satan. God disciplining and allowing his people to suffer the consequences so that the remnant can turn back to him.</p>
<p>When a metal caster is trying to extract metal from an ore, the ore must be refined. One must purify the metal. This purification involves a furnace that must increase in intensity until all impurities are gone. In this case, God had put his people into the furnace and the impurities were so deeply embedded that the metal would be nearly destroyed. And so the refining process was done in vain. And God rejected the ore.</p>
<h3>What do?</h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to have a hardened heart. I don&#8217;t want to have this kind of heart towards God. This makes the situation difficult for me and for everyone else around me. So why would I want to make this a difficult situation?</p>
<p>I have been in some difficult situations recently that involved a lot of sin on my part and sin on the part of some of my brothers. It was due to a character flaw in myself that happened to expose many hearts. All sin is bad. And these situations should never have happened. God isn&#8217;t planning on having me sin to refine other peoples&#8217; hearts. I must improve my character so that I won&#8217;t risk being a stumbling block to my brothers and sisters.</p>
<p>I have a new plan. Don&#8217;t try and look for flaws in someone else. Rather, just love everyone else and encourage as necessary. Prevent sin and make every effort to be at peace with everyone around me. This means that I must love everyone for who they are and not make prejudicial conclusions. I cannot pull my heart away from others. I must give my all.</p>
<p>At home. I must obey and honor my parents as I honor God. I will not sin if they ask me to (as they often ask me to do so). But I will honor them by obeying, giving, loving, and most of all, persevering in my life and doctrine (1 Timothy 4:16).</p>
<blockquote><p>And has just been said: &#8220;Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion.&#8221;&nbsp;— Hebrews 3:15 NIV</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doctrine</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 03:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As soon as it was night, the believers sent Paul and Silas away to Berea. On arriving there, they went&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-454"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>As soon as it was night, the believers sent Paul and Silas away to Berea. On arriving there, they went to the Jewish synagogue. Now the Berean Jews were of more noble character than those in Thessalonica, for they received the message with great eagerness and examined the Scriptures every day to see if what Paul said was true. As a result, many of them believed, as did also a number of prominent Greek women and many Greek men.&nbsp;— Acts 17:10-12 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>So there are many things that people can say about doctrines. They feel this about this Scripture and not that one. They feel that about the other Scripture. And you&#8217;re sitting there thinking, &#8220;where are you getting this from?&#8221; Or maybe you&#8217;re just sitting there agreeing without taking a second look.</p>
<p>I am part of a movement of churches that believes in studying the Scriptures for yourself so as to not get entangled by people&#8217;s opinions about any given topic (Acts 17:10-12). If there is a difference in &#8220;interpretation&#8221;, we bring it to light and we all get unified on what we believe. As such, there are many Scriptures that are very straightforward and do not require &#8220;interpretation&#8221;. Others, such as prophecies, require further study. An big example, is the study of the coming of the Kingdom of God. There are many prophecies about it in Isaiah, Daniel, Joel, and other prophets that came about during the time of the Babylonian exile. But good study reveals that all these prophecies are fulfilled in the book of Acts.</p>
<p>Then we have the topic of denominations. Why are there so many denominations of Christianity? Why is there so much division in a movement that is supposed to be one Church?</p>
<p>As a whole movement of Christianity, what makes us different from other religions? How are we different from Theraveda or Mahayana Buddhism? From Islam? From Judaism? What makes us different? How is our pursuit of salvation different from other religious traditions?</p>
<p>These are some of the thoughts and questions I was having. Whatever the cause of these questions, these are questions that shook and rocked my world recently. I did research into these religious traditions. I searched for answers that I thought I had already found. My lack of discipline in my quiet times with God had brought me to this point. Ultimately, I was about to give up on Christianity.</p>
<p>I related to Solomon&#8217;s thought process in Ecclesiastes:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Meaningless! Meaningless!&#8221; says the Teacher.&nbsp;&#8220;Utterly meaningless! Everything is meaningless.&#8221;&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 1:2 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote><p>Then I applied myself to the understanding of wisdom, and also of madness and folly, but I learned that this, too, is a chasing after the wind. For with much wisdom comes much sorrow; the more knowledge, the more grief.&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 1:17-18 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>Nothing meant anything to me. I was wondering whether things were really as they were. I lost myself in thought and missed class and work. I couldn&#8217;t figure things out. I was stuck in habitual sins but wondering whether or not these were really sins. I was questioning the nature of Creation, the nature of God, the heart, the soul, how connected an action is to the soul, how one can say that someone else is saved. And I realized that the more I searched for answers, the less satisfied I became with them. I decided that instead of searching for a revelation or some emotional experience, I would instead look at things as objectively as possible.</p>
<p>In Christianity, the life of Jesus and his relationship to God&nbsp;is the distinguishing trait of the religious tradition. In Buddhism, the teaching and reaching nirvana, the breaking of samsara is what is essential to the religious tradition. In Judaism, there is a hope and an expectation of God&#8217;s messiah to continue to rebuke the people of God. In Islam, there is the teaching and following of Mohammad. What makes me different?</p>
<p>At the age of 5, I was involved in an accident that sent me to the hospital. My dad was selling hot dogs in the streets of Downtown Los Angeles. Everyone loved his recipe and his business strategy. Soon hot dog stands like his sprang up all over Los Angeles. Everyone knew my dad. &#8220;Hot Dogs Adonai&#8221;, later renamed &#8220;Hot Dogs Jireh&#8221; was the name of my dad&#8217;s hot dog cart. It was during my aunt&#8217;s stay in our home.</p>
<p>We had humble circumstances. We weren&#8217;t living an extravagant life. But it was a life so much better than my parents had when they lived in Mexico. So on October 9th, 1999, my dad was selling his hot dogs just like every other day. My aunt was standing in the shade and she complained about the heat. My dad had a feeling that something was wrong. He smelled a gas leak. I was curious. He opened the bottom compartment to the cart and looked in. That&#8217;s when it happened. The gas made contact with the flame. I saw the flame shoot through the gas in the air and straight into the compartment my dad was looking into. The propane tank exploded in his face and the blast hit me all over my body. All I remember is the feeling of needles pinching and pulling my skin off. That&#8217;s the best way I can describe the pain I felt. I saw my mom rush over to me. My dad was slapping his face putting out flames. My mom lifted me onto a chair and was slapping my face with wet hands dousing the flames on my skin. I passed out. I remember haziness and an ambulance. I remember thinking it was so cool to be in an ambulance. The paramedics were putting needles into my arms and my mom was crying on the side. I passed out. I woke up at the hospital. They were taking me to a metal bin. They scrubbed my skin with steel wool. The 3rd degree burns were so deep that I felt as if the flames had engulfed me once more. Skin fell off.</p>
<p>I later found myself&nbsp;wrapped in white cloth in bed. I couldn&#8217;t move. I got one visitor, my pre-kindergarten teacher. I spent several months in recovery. There were many scary moments. There was a time that I flat-lined. They didn&#8217;t revive me and the medics&nbsp;gave up on me. And my mom protested. They were getting ready to cart me out and to bring in the next patient when I woke up asking why I hadn&#8217;t&nbsp;been taken to Griffith Park. Medics rushed in and out and some even&nbsp;covered their faces and ran out&nbsp;to the balcony and prayed to God (it was obvious). I moved back home and continued in recovery. Today I have no deep scars. I only have some small marks on my arms and hands that&nbsp;people do not notice unless I point it out.</p>
<p>I say all this because this is the first time I believed in God. This is not because of my parents indoctrinating me with their personal beliefs. It was of my own accord. I wanted to learn more.&nbsp;I was 5 years old and didn&#8217;t know how to appreciate life. So this fervor quickly died out.</p>
<p>When I began college, I began to question the idea of God. I wondered why I believed in God and had forgotten about this miracle that I had seen. It wasn&#8217;t long before I found myself in depression and stuck in ruts everywhere. I had no motivation and no zeal for learning. I just wanted to escape the world into&nbsp;fantasies. This led to many things. Sin after sin. It was then that I revisited my questions from childhood. I began to go to church at the request of one of my friends from college. Ultimately he felt that he didn&#8217;t need God. But I kept going. And I felt all the emotions and went to worship with a lot of people who had good hearts. But I was not taught to be a follower. I was not taught to be a worshiper in spirit and truth (John 4:23-24). I&nbsp;was later kicked out of school&nbsp;due to bad grades and my lack of understanding of how to manage life. I had to admit defeat to my parents and my family. My family had such high hopes for me and they were very disappointed. My parents, on the other hand, were very joyful to have me back home.</p>
<p>I began to attend a community college with the intent of returning to UC Berkeley. But my greatest challenge and time of learning came from my time at the community college. I learned to study the Bible and to teach the Bible. I learned what it meant to remain faithful and to be&nbsp;a pure man for God. It&#8217;s when I was baptized and began discipleship.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also the time that I&nbsp;began to try and learn wisdom and understanding from other cultures and other peoples. Specifically, I was interested in Japanese culture and religious philosophy. But that led me to more questioning. I was again caught up in&nbsp;trying to escape reality. Life got difficult. I watched more anime. I read other books and not my Bible. I watched all sorts of dramas that didn&#8217;t help me grow. Slowly I began to poison my thinking and to fall away in my heart.</p>
<p>So about going with the correct doctrine, I decided to look at my questions. After one month of questioning with no research and no effort made into reconciling with God, I went back to the Bible. I decided to pray to God once more.</p>
<p>I believe in a soul I believe that Jesus is God. I considered the psychoanalyses of Jesus and determined that he wasn&#8217;t just some crazy guy claiming to be God. He wasn&#8217;t lying. People have waged wars and have lost their lives for this belief. Countless martyrs have battled these other philosophies and found them fruitless. How can you know that you&#8217;ve lived before and have had past lives? I can&#8217;t really know. How can you know what there is after this life? I don&#8217;t know. Maybe it&#8217;s emptiness and maybe it&#8217;s another life. But I know that there is a man who claimed to be God and died for all. This act of love is&nbsp;a greater truth than anything I&#8217;ve ever seen.</p>
<p>If God so loved the world, and many people claim to be Christian, why is there so much hatred and sin in the world? They haven&#8217;t repented of their sins. They falsely call themselves Christian. They falsely claim to love others. But at the same time, there are people who are genuinely disciples of Christ. And can be very misunderstood because of one action where they let their sinful nature get the best of them. There is only what we know and what we can know. The rest is faith. We walk in faith. I choose this path of faith because it&#8217;s what&nbsp;makes the most sense. Buddhist teachings are not quite there.&nbsp;I can actually say that someone died for me. The Buddha didn&#8217;t die for me. He didn&#8217;t even want to share his great revelation. He did it anyway but he died. He will not come back and rescue. Even the Mahayana branch that refuses to fully achieve nirvana cannot say that they love as Jesus Christ did. Islam&nbsp;describes Jesus as a greater prophet than Mohammad. I am still learning. But learning without God is meaningless. Nobody&nbsp;will benefit. And working for others&nbsp;who do not understand what things are for is pointless. My purpose is simply to live for God. I repented of all my sins. I have considered that Creation alone is not the divine reality. Cause and effect&nbsp;is real. God is real.</p>
<blockquote><p>Now all has been heard; here is the conclusion of the matter: Fear God and keep his commandments, for this is the duty of all mankind. For God will bring every deed into judgment, including every hidden thing, whether it is good or evil.&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 12:13-14 NIV</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grace</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 03:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift of God — Ephesians 2:8</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span id="more-407"></span>I&#8217;ve heard it so many times. Many people like to say, &#8220;by grace we have been saved&#8221;. But I had to ask myself the question. What does grace mean? Why are there so many doctrines that differ on the concept of salvation by grace? Why do people say that they want to continue sinning so that God can have more grace?</p>
<p>I was recently able to share a bit of my testimony in front of my church. It was challenging to say the least. Not the part about speaking in front of the crowd, but the part about being sincere and being vulnerable to the point of shedding a tear or two.</p>
<p>This is what I shared:</p>
<p>When I think of the cross, I think grace. I don&#8217;t know about you, but I am a messed up person. There are so many things that I&#8217;d like to claim that I can do well. I have a knack for working with computers, learning languages, for learning and expressing myself clearly. Cool! None of it matters&#8230;</p>
<p>Turn with me to Ephesians 2.</p>
<blockquote><p>As for you, you were <strong>dead</strong> in your transgressions and sins, in which you used to live when you followed the ways of this world and of the ruler of the kingdom of the air, the spirit who is now at work in those who are disobedient. All of us also lived among them at one time, gratifying the cravings of our flesh and following its desires and thoughts. Like the rest, we were by nature deserving of wrath. But because of his great love for us, God, who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions—it is by grace you have been saved. And God raised us up with Christ and seated us with him in the heavenly realms in Christ Jesus, in order that in the coming ages he might show the incomparable riches of his grace, expressed in his kindness to us in Christ Jesus. For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the <strong>gift of God</strong>— not by works, so that no one can boast. For we are God’s handiwork, created in Christ Jesus <strong>to do good works</strong>, which God prepared in advance for us to do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I reflected on this passage. I was dead in my transgressions and sins. I was the kind of guy that nobody would hang around with. I have messed up so many times in my life, it&#8217;s impossible to say that <em>I&#8217;m</em> not a sinner.</p>
<p>When I was in high school, I had so much pride in myself! I used to think that I was the smartest at school. I would honestly believe that I was smarter than all of the students there. I joined the Academic Decathlon in order to fulfill my desire to be glorified. I thought that I would win medals and awards and scholarships and get so much glory. I was wrong. All I did was push people away. People who genuinely wanted to be my friends, I would punch them and tell them that they were worthless and not worth my time. Others I didn&#8217;t have the patience for. I met a guy who was so humble and so grateful that I even spoke to him. And I pushed him away too. I had no friends. And I had the illusion that my teacher was my friend. Just because he kept telling me that I was smart and &#8220;going places&#8221;. I delighted to think that the people who would bully me in middle school would be my employees one day or that I would make them suffer for what they did to me. I thought that by proving my parents wrong I would somehow get them to say that they were proud of me. They often told me so. But I felt nothing when they did say it. Because I felt the emptiness of vain glory. I hurt people and didn&#8217;t care. But I couldn&#8217;t figure out why I was so empty. I didn&#8217;t get <em>any</em> medals at the end of the competition. I cried that day. I was bitter at everyone. Everyone had a smile on their face. Everyone had worked hard and was friends with someone else. Everyone had the dream life.</p>
<p>Moving forward, I got into UC Berkeley. Hooray! [sarcasm]. I became worse. But now that I really didn&#8217;t know anyone, I felt the loneliness. My parents and family were not there anymore. I began to see how other students would sabotage each other&#8217;s work in order to be the top of the class. I began to see so much darkness in the world. I thought that I had it going and I had nothing. I messed up. I messed up thinking that I could go on living in impurity, insecurity, etc. I was not the smartest guy anymore. Everyone had equal or greater capacity. Mostly greater capacity. I was humbled out. I lost so much faith in my own ability. I thought that I had nothing to bring to this world. I wanted to leave the world.</p>
<p>The evening that I would go ahead with that plan, one of the guys who lived on the same floor as I did in the dorms literally had to drag me out of my room in order to get me to come to church. Now, it wasn&#8217;t the church that would tell me how to get saved, but it was definitely a wake-up call. I was raised in a religious household. I was sick of God. But this time, I resonated with the message of hope. I had lived a life of sin. I was heartless, prideful, insecure, impure, hateful, dissensuous, immoral, and worst of all, guilty.</p>
<p>I studied the Bible and started seeking God with all my heart. And on March 20, 2015, I was baptized for the forgiveness of my sins. I made a decision to live my life as a disciple of Christ. Did I stop sinning the way I did? I tried my best not to sin, but I had to learn and unlearn at the same time. I would argue with people about who was right about the Bible and who wasn&#8217;t. I made mistake after mistake after mistake. I do not deserve forgiveness. And yet, I have forgiveness. I do not deserve the love of God and yet I have it. I do not deserve the death of Christ, and yet He has risen. Grace simply means that God had mercy. God had mercy on a hopeless sinner like myself. God gave it all for me. Why should I continue sinning? And yet I continue to sin. However, it is most definitely <strong><em>not</em></strong> a license for me to sin.</p>
<p>But I still have one message of hope. As I think of the cross, I think of Romans 5:8</p>
<blockquote><p>But God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have been made alive in Christ. I am no longer subject to the pain of sin. I am no longer defined by my sin. I have hope! And I would be selfish and heartless not to share this hope with someone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
