<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>interesting &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/interesting/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>interesting &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptable sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardened hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-699"></span></p>
<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just posting my notes.</p>
<p>The alarms aren&#8217;t sounding&#8230; God has warned his people of the consequences of their sin. Nobody listens. In fact, they shut their ears.</p>
<p>This is why the anger of God burns&#8230; They do not listen!</p>
<p>v14. To dress a wound improperly as though it were not serious is a very serious deceit. This hardening goes from the leaders to the people. If the leaders aren&#8217;t ashamed of their own conduct, the people won&#8217;t be ashamed either.&nbsp;This leads to a definitive hardening in the hearts of many.</p>
<p>v16. This is a crossroads. Every time I get discipling, it is a crossroads. I can choose to follow God&#8217;s way or my own way. God&#8217;s way: the good way, where I will find rest for my soul.</p>
<p>This is a case of discipline. When I was younger, my mom would often discipline me by threatening to make an example of me in front of my classmates. Man.. how I feared that! I feared that my deeds would be exposed. I feared that I would be exposed as some sort of incredibly immature guy. For a long time, I held on to this fear. And my mom never came through with the threats. I hardened myself to her and resisted her discipline. I&#8217;m very grateful that God did this for me. Later on, I would be disciplined by my brother in the church and, initially, I resisted and didn&#8217;t understand what was going on. And all that pains me now is that anyone with a hardened heart cannot please God. I couldn&#8217;t please my mom because I had started to dislike her and her discipline.</p>
<p>v20. Sacrifices that are fancy, much labor, or even great sacrifices aren&#8217;t pleasing to God and are, in fact, worship in vain when my heart is hard.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lord says:&nbsp;&#8220;These people come near to me with their mouth and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me.&nbsp;Their worship of me is based on merely human rules they have been taught&#8230;&#8221;&nbsp;— Isaiah 29:13 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>These sacrifices aren&#8217;t even acceptable!</p>
<p>v22. God will bring discipline! God warned his people and then disaster struck.</p>
<p>v26.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Suddenly the destroyer will come upon us.&#8221;&nbsp;— Jeremiah 6:26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>And this is the hand of God, not Satan. God disciplining and allowing his people to suffer the consequences so that the remnant can turn back to him.</p>
<p>When a metal caster is trying to extract metal from an ore, the ore must be refined. One must purify the metal. This purification involves a furnace that must increase in intensity until all impurities are gone. In this case, God had put his people into the furnace and the impurities were so deeply embedded that the metal would be nearly destroyed. And so the refining process was done in vain. And God rejected the ore.</p>
<h3>What do?</h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to have a hardened heart. I don&#8217;t want to have this kind of heart towards God. This makes the situation difficult for me and for everyone else around me. So why would I want to make this a difficult situation?</p>
<p>I have been in some difficult situations recently that involved a lot of sin on my part and sin on the part of some of my brothers. It was due to a character flaw in myself that happened to expose many hearts. All sin is bad. And these situations should never have happened. God isn&#8217;t planning on having me sin to refine other peoples&#8217; hearts. I must improve my character so that I won&#8217;t risk being a stumbling block to my brothers and sisters.</p>
<p>I have a new plan. Don&#8217;t try and look for flaws in someone else. Rather, just love everyone else and encourage as necessary. Prevent sin and make every effort to be at peace with everyone around me. This means that I must love everyone for who they are and not make prejudicial conclusions. I cannot pull my heart away from others. I must give my all.</p>
<p>At home. I must obey and honor my parents as I honor God. I will not sin if they ask me to (as they often ask me to do so). But I will honor them by obeying, giving, loving, and most of all, persevering in my life and doctrine (1 Timothy 4:16).</p>
<blockquote><p>And has just been said: &#8220;Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion.&#8221;&nbsp;— Hebrews 3:15 NIV</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faithfulness, Or Lack Thereof</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 03:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s quiet time reading was pretty interesting. I read Jeremiah 2 and expected to see the sin of Israel that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-81"></span>Today&#8217;s quiet time reading was pretty interesting. I read Jeremiah 2 and expected to see the sin of Israel that brought it into ruin. But I didn&#8217;t expect it to be worse. Jeremiah 2 begins to explain how God feels when we sin against him. This was flat convicting.</p>
<p>I realize more and more the reality of the people forsaking God. Today, this world goes to great lengths to declare God as a myth or as some fairy tale made up to satisfy the needs of a weak people.</p>
<p>But myths aside, nobody can prove or disprove God. It is up to the person whether or not they want to believe in whatever they want to believe. So when a person comes to acknowledge the existence of God, they may at first be super excited! I mean&#8230; who wouldn&#8217;t? The answer to a question so complex as this is definitely satisfying. But nonetheless it requires faith.</p>
<p>Faith is something that the Jews lacked throughout their history. Jeremiah comes at the dawn of the darkest time in Jewish history. Jeremiah is young and is not confident in the words of God. But regardless, Jeremiah has enough faith to confront Israel in its lack of commitment towards God.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">The word of the Lord came to me: <span id="en-NIV-18968">“Go and proclaim in the hearing of Jerusalem:</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">“This is what the Lord says:</p>
<div style="text-align:left;">
<p>“‘I remember the devotion of your youth,<br />
how as a bride you loved me<br />
and followed me through the wilderness,<br />
through a land not sown.<br />
<span id="en-NIV-18969">Israel was holy to the Lord,</span><br />
the firstfruits of his harvest;<br />
all who devoured her were held guilty,<br />
and disaster overtook them,’”<br />
declares the Lord.</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align:left;">
<p><span id="en-NIV-18970">Hear the word of the Lord, you descendants of Jacob,</span><br />
all you clans of Israel.</p>
</div>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span id="en-NIV-18971">This is what the Lord says:</span></p>
<div>
<p style="text-align:left;">“What fault did your ancestors find in me,<br />
that they strayed so far from me?<br />
They followed worthless idols<br />
and became worthless themselves. — Jeremiah 2:1-5 NIV</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<div class="poetry top-05">
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">There are a couple of points to make here. The Jews were once devoted to God! They had a strong faith and they held their own (with God&#8217;s help) against other kingdoms. The Israelites, at this point, were people who were true followers of God. But what happened? That&#8217;s exactly the question that God asks the Israelites in verse 5. What happened?</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">Today, the modern Christian is very hard to respect. In the United States, the average &#8220;Christian&#8221; goes to church on Sundays. But is that all there is to devoting one&#8217;s life to God? There are so many churches today that preach that all you have to do is believe that God is real and that you will receive a salvation for sins. Somehow your past sins will be erased and somehow you will get to heaven. Many have also left out the part where you live your life for God. Many have left out the part where you need to repent and change!</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">Again, what did people see in God that they left him? Why is it that so many people refuse to believe in God? Is it because there was an unanswered prayer? Is it because someone who claimed to be Christian wronged them? Is it because their parents died? Is it because they think it&#8217;s silly because they think that others think it&#8217;s silly (peer pressure)? People begin to follow other idols such as the dream job, the ideal family, the American Dream, the next promotion, money. How does this compare with the God of the Universe? What happened to God being GOD? Then again, how does this apply to myself?</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">When I first became a Christian, I was very excited. I was all about making sure that everyone knew the truth regardless of whether or not they liked it. Now, of course, there are ways to talk to other people. In my nature, I wanted to put others down to show that I was right. And sadly, that turned away many people. I was so focused on trying to show others that I was right that I did many things that I laugh at today. And that&#8217;s not even that long ago!</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">And yet, I find myself thinking about what I did today. I did not have a very productive day. I did not have class today and I felt like I could take the day off. You know those days when we feel like not doing anything? Well, today was one of those days for me. But that means that I was not about my life&#8217;s purpose for a day. And since my life&#8217;s purpose is to try to align myself to God&#8217;s purpose, how can I say I had a good day? How can I say that I had a productive day? It&#8217;s crazy how the Scriptures can cut my heart&#8230;</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">This quiet time will have to continue through tomorrow. This is good stuff and I want to make sure that I have a thorough understanding.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
