<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/hardened-hearts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/maralkan-logo-favicon-3.png</url>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptable sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardened hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/">Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-699"></span></p>
<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just posting my notes.</p>
<p>The alarms aren&#8217;t sounding&#8230; God has warned his people of the consequences of their sin. Nobody listens. In fact, they shut their ears.</p>
<p>This is why the anger of God burns&#8230; They do not listen!</p>
<p>v14. To dress a wound improperly as though it were not serious is a very serious deceit. This hardening goes from the leaders to the people. If the leaders aren&#8217;t ashamed of their own conduct, the people won&#8217;t be ashamed either.&nbsp;This leads to a definitive hardening in the hearts of many.</p>
<p>v16. This is a crossroads. Every time I get discipling, it is a crossroads. I can choose to follow God&#8217;s way or my own way. God&#8217;s way: the good way, where I will find rest for my soul.</p>
<p>This is a case of discipline. When I was younger, my mom would often discipline me by threatening to make an example of me in front of my classmates. Man.. how I feared that! I feared that my deeds would be exposed. I feared that I would be exposed as some sort of incredibly immature guy. For a long time, I held on to this fear. And my mom never came through with the threats. I hardened myself to her and resisted her discipline. I&#8217;m very grateful that God did this for me. Later on, I would be disciplined by my brother in the church and, initially, I resisted and didn&#8217;t understand what was going on. And all that pains me now is that anyone with a hardened heart cannot please God. I couldn&#8217;t please my mom because I had started to dislike her and her discipline.</p>
<p>v20. Sacrifices that are fancy, much labor, or even great sacrifices aren&#8217;t pleasing to God and are, in fact, worship in vain when my heart is hard.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lord says:&nbsp;&#8220;These people come near to me with their mouth and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me.&nbsp;Their worship of me is based on merely human rules they have been taught&#8230;&#8221;&nbsp;— Isaiah 29:13 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>These sacrifices aren&#8217;t even acceptable!</p>
<p>v22. God will bring discipline! God warned his people and then disaster struck.</p>
<p>v26.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Suddenly the destroyer will come upon us.&#8221;&nbsp;— Jeremiah 6:26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>And this is the hand of God, not Satan. God disciplining and allowing his people to suffer the consequences so that the remnant can turn back to him.</p>
<p>When a metal caster is trying to extract metal from an ore, the ore must be refined. One must purify the metal. This purification involves a furnace that must increase in intensity until all impurities are gone. In this case, God had put his people into the furnace and the impurities were so deeply embedded that the metal would be nearly destroyed. And so the refining process was done in vain. And God rejected the ore.</p>
<h3>What do?</h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to have a hardened heart. I don&#8217;t want to have this kind of heart towards God. This makes the situation difficult for me and for everyone else around me. So why would I want to make this a difficult situation?</p>
<p>I have been in some difficult situations recently that involved a lot of sin on my part and sin on the part of some of my brothers. It was due to a character flaw in myself that happened to expose many hearts. All sin is bad. And these situations should never have happened. God isn&#8217;t planning on having me sin to refine other peoples&#8217; hearts. I must improve my character so that I won&#8217;t risk being a stumbling block to my brothers and sisters.</p>
<p>I have a new plan. Don&#8217;t try and look for flaws in someone else. Rather, just love everyone else and encourage as necessary. Prevent sin and make every effort to be at peace with everyone around me. This means that I must love everyone for who they are and not make prejudicial conclusions. I cannot pull my heart away from others. I must give my all.</p>
<p>At home. I must obey and honor my parents as I honor God. I will not sin if they ask me to (as they often ask me to do so). But I will honor them by obeying, giving, loving, and most of all, persevering in my life and doctrine (1 Timothy 4:16).</p>
<blockquote><p>And has just been said: &#8220;Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion.&#8221;&nbsp;— Hebrews 3:15 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/">Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
