<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jesus &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/jesus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:09:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Jesus &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Excellent Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excellent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-363"></span>Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just a superficial remedy. He heals completely and thoroughly, leaving no blemish behind.</p>
<p>In Mark 7, Jesus healed a deaf and mute man. Now, being sensitive to those who are deaf and mute, this is something that, according to the hearing world, is considered a disease of some sort. But Jesus did something incredible.</p>
<blockquote><p>Then Jesus left the vicinity of Tyre and went through Sidon, down to the Sea of Galilee and into the region of the Decapolis. There some people brought to him a man who was deaf and could hardly talk, and they begged Jesus to place his hand on him.</p>
<p>After he took him aside, away from the crowd, Jesus put his fingers into the man’s ears. Then he spit and touched the man’s tongue. He looked up to heaven and with a deep sigh said to him, “Ephphatha!” (which means “Be opened!”). At this, the man’s ears were opened, his tongue was loosened and he began to speak plainly.</p>
<p>Jesus commanded them not to tell anyone. But the more he did so, the more they kept talking about it. People were overwhelmed with amazement. “He has done everything well,” they said. “He even makes the deaf hear and the mute speak.” — Mark 7:31-37 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>Today, modern procedures for someone to hear requires Deaf people to have an intrusive device that looks obvious on them. These devices, can be very painful experiences to those who have lived deaf lives. I&#8217;ve heard many accounts of these hearing aids comparing the sudden influx of noise to a massive train wreck playing in our ears at volume levels too intense for us to bear. Deaf people with hearing aids must go through a lot in order to be part of the hearing world. Again, these hearing aids cause massive &#8220;migraine&#8221; headaches that are too much to bear.</p>
<p>But Jesus healed a man at a time when this was not even a possibility in people&#8217;s minds. Jesus installed a language into a man&#8217;s mind. He cured a man of would-be headaches and even have the man muscle memory for the tongue, that he would be able to speak possibly as if he had spoken the language his whole life. That&#8217;s amazing!</p>
<p>My major in school is cognitive science. Because of it, I&#8217;m able to appreciate the fact that this man had to receive a sudden influx of information into his brain, had to have many neural pathways changed, and he needed to have nerve paths hardened before Jesus&#8217;s fingers left the man&#8217;s ears. And that&#8217;s not even touching the fact that the man&#8217;s ears are now sensitive to sound. The cochlea, the inner ear, is now able to perceive sound the way it is supposed to. This man was also <em>probably</em> able to communicate the wonders of God and Jesus in sign language as well! This was definitely a contribution to the world evangelization described in the book of Acts. I say the word &#8220;probably&#8221; with caution; it&#8217;s not in the Bible!</p>
<p>Now, Jesus loved this man and healed him completely. I now ask myself this question&#8230; How do I love others? Do I love someone &#8220;just enough&#8221;? Or do I go out of my way to love my brothers, sisters, and those outside? I had a conversation with a fellow student regarding the Catholic faith. We differed on the basis that I hold the Bible to be the ultimate and final authority in all things related to God and my life. But he holds the Church to be the final authority and the Bible is merely a book of guidelines. We differ and I don&#8217;t hold it against him. But I do tell him to challenge his way of thinking. This is the primary way by which false doctrines came into the church. This is the main reason why so many people think they&#8217;re doing all things right. This is why people believe that they can be saved with a simple prayer. It&#8217;s because churches have subjected the Bible to be merely a book of guidelines. It&#8217;s not the Word of God. It&#8217;s instead just a set of inspired writings that have man&#8217;s intentions written all over them. He thinks that one receives salvation through the Eucharist tradition of the Catholic church.</p>
<p>Regardless of how much I know, I still will not be able to win him over using knowledge of the Scriptures. It&#8217;s loving excellently as Jesus did. It&#8217;s dying to myself and not getting into quarrels about knowledge. It&#8217;s truly living a pure life. It&#8217;s taking care of my life and my doctrine.</p>
<blockquote><p><sup>16</sup> Watch your life and doctrine closely. Persevere in them, because if you do, you will save both yourself and your hearers. — 1 Timothy 4:16</p></blockquote>
<p>And also:</p>
<blockquote><p>1 Jesus knew that the Father had put all things under his power, and that he had come from God and was returning to God; so he got up from the meal, took off his outer clothing, and wrapped a towel around his waist. After that, he poured water into a basin and began to wash his disciples’ feet, drying them with the towel that was wrapped around him.</p>
<p>He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, “Lord, are you going to wash my feet?”</p>
<p>Jesus replied, “You do not realize now what I am doing, but later you will understand.”</p>
<p>“No,” said Peter, “you shall never wash my feet.”</p>
<p>Jesus answered, “Unless I wash you, you have no part with me.”</p>
<p>“Then, Lord,” Simon Peter replied, “not just my feet but my hands and my head as well!”</p>
<p>12 When he had finished washing their feet, he put on his clothes and returned to his place. “Do you understand what I have done for you?” he asked them. “You call me ‘Teacher’ and ‘Lord,’ and rightly so, for that is what I am. Now that I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also should wash one another’s feet. I have set you an example that you should do as I have done for you. Very truly I tell you, no servant is greater than his master, nor is a messenger greater than the one who sent him. Now that you know these things, you will be blessed if you do them.” — John 13:1-9, 12-17 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Just as Jesus loved, so I should love. There are times when I don&#8217;t feel like loving my brother. But how can I love God, who I can&#8217;t see, if I can&#8217;t love my brother, who I can see? Jesus loved excellently. I will do so as well.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">-M</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Being Faithful</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 01:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I&#8217;m continuing to read Mark&#8217;s account of the ministry of Jesus. I think it&#8217;s interesting how Jesus had a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-240"></span>Today, I&#8217;m continuing to read Mark&#8217;s account of the ministry of Jesus. I think it&#8217;s interesting how Jesus had a heart to help everyone but wanted to remain on the down low until it was his time. Curiously, there&#8217;s the aspect of Jesus that many people can often overlook.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Very early in the morning, while it was still dark, Jesus got up, left the house and went off to a solitary place, where <strong>he prayed</strong>. Simon and his companions went to look for him, and when they found him, they exclaimed: “Everyone is looking for you!” Jesus replied, “Let us go somewhere else—to the nearby villages—so I can preach there also. <strong>That is why I have come</strong>.” So he traveled throughout Galilee, preaching in their synagogues and driving out demons. — Mark 1:35-39 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Prayer and Reading</h3>
<p>Jesus had a daily relationship with God. As I learn to imitate Christ, I must have a daily relationship with God. How can I be best friends with someone if I don&#8217;t talk to them? How can I say I love God if I don&#8217;t talk to him or read his Word? Again, I can reference Romans 10:17 NIV.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">Consequently, faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the <strong>word about Christ</strong>. — Romans 10:17 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Jesus had a daily relationship with God. But another thing to note, is that he always had time with God before he did anything throughout the day. We don&#8217;t have his prayer but it&#8217;s probably for strength. Why would anyone want to love people who are only interested in you because you provide some sort of advantage and no real friendship? Jesus prayed and then he decided to go elsewhere so that others may hear his preaching. So far, the only thing we know is that he has preached about the coming of the kingdom of God. And since the kingdom of God has come near, people must repent and believe that it is good news!</p>
<p>But what does this message that he preaches have to do with Christ? In a future post, I will talk about the kingdom of God in further detail. But it leaves me with obvious impression that Jesus is not preaching about himself. He is preaching about something important that is to come and is very near.</p>
<h3>Purpose</h3>
<p>When Jesus told his first disciples to follow him, he talked to fishermen with words that they knew about. He used their profession to explain to them that he has a new purpose for them. Now, these are his disciples. Today, people think that a disciple is so much more than a Christian. A Christian, for some reason, means that you go to church and have some sort of intellectual belief in a supernatural being that he/she calls God. But a disciple is a follower, a student, a friend, an apprentice. How are they different? Is a disciple more faithful than a Christian? Is a Christian then, some term that you can use freely to say that you believe in a supernatural being?</p>
<p>In the Greek, χριστιανους is the word used in the 1550 Stephanus New Testament. This word means &#8220;follower of Christ&#8221; or, depending on the translation, &#8220;little Christ&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>Then Barnabas went to Tarsus to look for Saul, and when he found him, he brought him to Antioch. So for a whole year Barnabas and Saul met with the church and taught great numbers of people. The <strong>disciples</strong> were called <strong>Christians</strong> first at Antioch. — Acts 11:25-26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>All of the followers of Christ were disciples. Nobody ever dared to call himself a Christian. It was a derogatory term used to condemn people. So what happened that suddenly people are proud to call themselves &#8220;Christian&#8221; but not &#8220;disciples&#8221;? Is the word &#8220;disciple&#8221; too strong? They&#8217;re the same thing! So, if you&#8217;re still thinking that you&#8217;re one of these but not the other, you might need to check yourself. If you&#8217;re not a &#8220;disciple&#8221;, you&#8217;re not being a real Christian.</p>
<p>Anyway, Jesus gave his disciples a new purpose for their lives. Now, their purpose in life is to go out and &#8220;fish for people&#8221;. Interestingly, this is Jesus&#8217; first and last teaching according to Matthew and Mark just before his ascension to his disciples. Therefore it must hold some significance. Jesus gave his disciples a purpose to their lives. Now, Jesus taught everyone the same things. Why would that teaching change for me? I&#8217;m not an &#8220;apostle&#8221;! Does that make me exempt from Jesus&#8217; teaching? Is talking to someone too hard? Faith is not about having an intellectual idea that God exists. One doesn&#8217;t say that he/she has faith that a chair will not break and then proceed to never sit on it! If somebody has faith that a chair will not break when he/she sits on it, he/she will sit on it. If I have faith that Jesus is God, then I must do something about it!</p>
<p>I have to ask myself: am I about my purpose as a disciple of Christ? Since I go to school and have a job, is my purpose about my school, career, job, family? Is my purpose to please God or please myself?</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">Then Jesus came to them and said, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age.” — Matthew 28:18-20 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unconditional Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconditional love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-189"></span>I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night that I need to have more faith to be able to be strong in all situations. (Romans 10:17 NIV)</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">And a voice came from heaven: &#8220;You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased.&#8221; — Mark 1:11 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">A Christian is a follower of Jesus. Therefore, an imitator of Jesus. God was well pleased with Jesus. Therefore, as I imitate Christ, God will be pleased with me just as Jesus pleased him in his time. What&#8217;s crazy is that God has long encouraged prophets to remain steadfast and to know his heart. But this time it was different. This time, God was pleased with Jesus before he had started his ministry! Already, this distinguishes Jesus from all of the prophets.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The question here is, how do I imitate Christ? Simple, I must learn what Jesus did and taught. How do I learn that? I can&#8217;t rely on anyone to teach me. I must do it for myself. It&#8217;s my personal relationship with God.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">So then, what are the teachings of Jesus? I guess I&#8217;m going to learn more and more as I continue to read the Bible.</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">Application for Today</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">Today, it seems, I will have to follow the example of Christ.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Love must be sincere.</strong> Hate what is evil; cling to what is good. <strong>Be devoted to one another in love. Honor one another above yourselves.</strong> Never be lacking in zeal, but keep your spiritual fervor, serving the Lord. Be joyful in hope, patient in affliction, faithful in prayer. Share with the Lord’s people who are in need. Practice hospitality.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Bless those who persecute you; bless and do not curse. Rejoice with those who rejoice; mourn with those who mourn. Live in harmony with one another. Do not be proud, but be willing to associate with people of low position. Do not be conceited.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Do not repay anyone evil for evil. Be careful to do what is right in the eyes of everyone. <strong>If it is possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone.</strong> Do not take revenge, my dear friends, but leave room for God’s wrath, for it is written: “It is mine to avenge; I will repay,” says the Lord. On the contrary:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">“If your enemy is hungry, feed him;<br />
if he is thirsty, give him something to drink.<br />
In doing this, you will heap burning coals on his head.”<br />
Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good. — Romans 12:9-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">and</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">We love because he first loved us. Whoever claims to love God yet hates a brother or sister is a <strong>liar</strong>. For whoever does not love their brother and sister, whom they have seen, <strong>cannot love God</strong>, whom they have not seen. And <strong>he has given us this command</strong>: Anyone who loves God must also love their brother and sister. — 1 John 4:19-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Christ taught many times throughout his time on earth and through his apostles&#8217; writings that we must have love for one another. I can imitate Christ by having love for my brothers (<em>adelphoi</em> means brothers and sisters). How can I love my brothers? I can definitely start by changing my character. So many times, I thought that everyone else had to change because I was doing everything right. I love people, I give sacrificially, I do more things (in my opinion) than others. But that doesn&#8217;t make me righteous. When someone ignores me I get butthurt and I tend to pull away my love because I think it&#8217;s not worth it to love a person who will not appreciate my love. But Christ commands us to love as he did. He loved despite the rejection of the apostles when he was turned in to the authorities. He loved always. So I must also always love even in the face of rejection. That way, I will overcome evil with good. That way I can imitate Christ and live a life pleasing to God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
