<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>the struggle against sin &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/the-struggle-against-sin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>the struggle against sin &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Godly Sorrow</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[godly sorrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the struggle against sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God pours out his heart on all the people of Israel because they constantly forsake him and Jeremiah (or who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-104"></span>God pours out his heart on all the people of Israel because they constantly forsake him and Jeremiah (or who knows??) records in the second chapter. Now that I read it, I feel it applies to me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">&#8220;&#8230; Has a nation ever changed its gods? (Yet they are not gods at all.)<br />
But my people have exchanged their glorious God for worthless idols.<br />
Be appalled at this, you heavens, and shudder with great horror,” declares the Lord.<br />
“My people have committed two sins: They have forsaken me, the spring of living water, and have dug their own cisterns, broken cisterns that cannot hold water. &#8230;&#8221; — Jeremiah 2:11-13 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">It is not a secret that we are sinners. That I am a sinner. There are times when I continue to do the same thing over and over again. It&#8217;s not that I can&#8217;t control it&#8230; It&#8217;s that I deliberately want to sin. There&#8217;s no excuse where I can say that I accidentally sinned (though, it does happen when I unintentionally hurt someone else). The point is, I feel like God is telling me that I am like Israel, exchanging the glory of God for temporary pleasures or for lies.</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">What do?</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">So what do I do about it? James 5 tells me that I must confess my sins to another disciple and have him pray for me that I may be healed. And I must reciprocate to anyone who confesses their sins to me. But more than that, I must have godly sorrow.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death. See what this godly sorrow has produced in you: what earnestness, what eagerness to clear yourselves, what indignation, what alarm, what longing, what concern, what readiness to see justice done. At every point you have proved yourselves to be innocent in this matter. So even though I wrote to you, it was neither on account of the one who did the wrong nor on account of the injured party, but rather that before God you could see for yourselves how devoted to us you are. — 2 Corinthians 7:10-12 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Paul talks about the difference between feeling guilty about sin and actually doing something about it. Whenever I&#8217;m in sin, I tend to drop into worldly sorrow and beat myself up, regretting the past. It&#8217;s very difficult to get into a godly sorrow. Every time this happens, I seem to grasp a bit more that I cannot understand why God would forgive me. And yet, God forgives. He extended forgiveness to the Israelites through repentance. Unfortunately, they didn&#8217;t repent and change their ways. Seeing that I have the opportunity to repent fully of my sins, I must take that chance and fully repent.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">What does that look like?</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">Repentance</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">Repentance is turning away from something in the opposite direction. So if I were to repent of going to my friend&#8217;s house, I would simply turn around and go back to my house. Simple concept. Easier said than done.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">For myself, there are certain things that I can absolutely get rid of so that I may have greater self-control. Things such as my media consumption at home can be limited in various ways. Other things such as my association with people who like to do things that I once loved to do. Of course, I&#8217;m not going to completely run someone off. But I can move away from them and protect my purity and good character (as if I had great character&#8230;). Will that solve my problems? No. I must constantly be in prayer about these things. I really am unable to do this alone. That&#8217;s why I rely on my brothers and sisters in the faith. My brothers especially help me stay focused and pure. My sisters help me stay humble every time anything comes out of my mouth.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Will I do it? Definitely. Will I forsake God like the Israelites did for some temporary pleasures? No. I cannot betray God like that. I cannot leave the Kingdom of God for the World!!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">You&#8217;re probably reading this and are wondering why I would ever post something so publicly vulnerable on the Internet. I don&#8217;t mind people knowing my life. I leave this so that someone can maybe gain something from it. Maybe someone can come to know that there is hope in life. Life is not just your job and your school. It&#8217;s more than your mom, dad, brothers, and sisters. There is a God!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
