<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Heritage &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/heritage/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Heritage &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Blue Beetle</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexican American]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viva Mexico]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;We&#8217;re invisible to people like that, Jaime&#8221; Milagros from the Blue Beetle (2023) When I was seven years old, growing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re invisible to people like that, Jaime&#8221;</p>
<cite>Milagros from the Blue Beetle (2023)</cite></blockquote>



<p>When I was seven years old, growing up in the projects in Los Angeles, I learned about my Mexican heritage. I transferred to an elementary school that had a Magnet program (a school program that focuses kids onto a career path). This Math/Science/Tech Magnet school promised to put me onto a career path in the STEM field and promised to open doors for me that would allow me to do just that. It was at this school where I met African Americans for the first time. I distinctly remember feeling left out all the time because I had only learned to speak English two years before and I still needed ESL (English as a Second Language) classes. I learned about my Mexican heritage. I had never noticed myself as different until then. After two years there, I hated my experience. I had one friend but I was always picked on for being Mexican. I moved back to my old elementary school. I walked into my fourth grade class feeling like an outsider. My mom never allowed me to make friends with the <em>barrio</em>. I had missed out on three years with my classmates (I missed my entire first grade). I remember feeling like an outsider but it still felt like home.</p>



<p>I stayed with my classmates but the feeling never really went away. I remained an outsider because I was not allowed to cross the street to hang out with my school friends. Middle school came and I met the Asian American clicks. I found myself drifting between clicks. My closest friend was a Chinese kid. He and I got into trouble roaming the school halls during lunch (the halls were closed during lunch). I met a White kid and tried making friends with him only to be threatened by him. I didn&#8217;t realize I had met an Emo kid. This Emo White kid went on to become a dealer in powder and I stayed away from him. Despite the fact that I had one friend, I always felt alone. This feeling of loneliness pushed my one friend away and I sought another friendship. This time, I befriended a new kid on the block. I showed him where everything was and we became friends. He would come over to my place and we would play video games when my parents weren&#8217;t home. But we pushed it too far once and my parents came home early to surprise me. Needless to say, they banned him from going anywhere near me. I had no friends again.</p>



<p>I decided to go to a different high school that nobody else in my neighborhood attended. That school had a Math/Science/Tech Magnet. I went there because I hated the local bully so I just wanted to get away. At this school, I met a very diverse student body. I drifted and befriended a group of girls that everyone considered losers. I remember believing that I was, too, a loser and I could never hope to really get a pretty girl or make deep friendships.</p>



<p>I hated my parents and my Mexican heritage. They always cited our heritage as the reason why I should only make friends with my family members. I felt like they did not understand that they were hurting me. I didn&#8217;t get along with my siblings. I tried to have my parents deported out of sheer hatred. They never meant to harm me. The opposite was true. They really loved me and wanted the best for me. I was not successful (for which I am beyond grateful to God that He did not allow that to happen). They believed that I could never count on any friends I made because at the end of the day, only my family would be there for me. I hated that idea and rejected my family and my heritage. I made a concerted effort to try to speak English without a Mexican accent. I decided to learn to speak other languages because I thought it would make me not Mexican. I succeeded and I chose to go to whatever college was furthest from my family. I wanted to be something else just not Mexican. I hated the racism that my parents experienced. I hated that my family had suffered so much and they had to do it all on their own. My dad was mugged and he had to surrender ALL of our money. My mom had to carry a 100-pound bag of perfumes selling door-to-door every day for 15 hours a day just to put food on our table and say that they were on their way to the ever-elusive American Dream. My mom&#8217;s immediate family had abandoned her when she arrived in the States. They were around and would come to my birthday party. But they never lifted a finger to help my parents when we really needed it the most. My dad&#8217;s family&#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say I just met them for the first time now that I&#8217;m 29 years old. My parents taught me that family was everything but it was not true for them. So why should I love being Mexican? I also abandoned my once true faith in God. I became an atheist.</p>



<p>In college I lost myself. I got into self-destructive behavior and became depressed and gave myself over to pornography addictions because it was just better to feel that over the immensely negative perspective I had of my family. I proclaimed to my roommates that there was no God and that I only believed in myself. I was going to get out of my situation. I was determined but I had no real purpose or mission. I felt empty and I saw that everyone around me seemed oppressed by some sort of darkness in their life. Everyone was clamoring to be the very top of the class&#8230; and for what?</p>



<p>It was at this point that I contemplated suicide. I was hopeless and miserable. On the outside I smiled but I was flaking away like a very slow Thanos snap. I planned it out and decided on a day and time. I had everything ready. The hour that I was going to do it, one of my roommates, a skinny Chinese kid, burst into my dorm and asked me to go with him to Southside Berkeley to get dinner. I declined his offer and told him I was busy. But Matthew did not give up. He insisted and stood up to me. I just HAD to go with him because he felt unsafe walking through the dark part of campus. I reluctantly agreed and decided that I could postpone my self-harm behavior to help someone else. That broke my feeling of emptiness. At the end of our walk, he led me into an office space and I saw a big group of Asians that looked way too friendly for my liking. I got my Korean BBQ and sat down. It turns out he brought me to a Bible study. I was furious at him. I HATED GOD! I felt a rage that I desperately tried to calm. I didn&#8217;t know it but Matthew saved my life that day. To this day, I owe him a debt of gratitude. I calmed down and listened to the lesson. I don&#8217;t remember what the lesson was about but I distinctly remember raising my hand because I wanted to be an active participant all of a sudden. I blurted out that Jesus was my friend. I remember thinking, &#8220;Why the &#8212;- did I just say that out loud? I don&#8217;t even believe that &#8212;-.&#8221;</p>



<p>I now wanted to be an Asian. Chinese folks had always been kind to me ever since I met them. I went to every Bible study meeting because I felt comfortable. I made my first deep friendships in my life. I never wanted to let go. But my grades were slipping and my depression was still going. I was placed on Academic Probation and then I was dismissed from the University. I stayed another year with the Asian church. Until one day, one of the guys confronted me: &#8220;You should stop being prideful and go home to face the music with your family.&#8221; I was terrified because they didn&#8217;t know I had been dismissed. I hid it from my family.</p>



<p>I had to face my family and my heritage again. I didn&#8217;t want to go. But James, my confronter, was adamant that I would not be welcome to continue living with at the church household. For my own good, I needed to leave. I quit my job and moved back to Los Angeles that same week&#8230; feeling defeated and nauseous.</p>



<p>I apologized to my mom for the first time for attempting to deport her and my dad. I promised that I would change and be different. I set a boundary with my parents. I would no longer help them on Sundays with their business because I wanted to go to church. They gave me a very hard time because they said that they had just gotten me back and they weren&#8217;t going to allow this. I didn&#8217;t listen. I went to church at the Los Angeles branch of the same church. But I didn&#8217;t have the same relationships that I had built in Berkeley. I felt alone again. Worse, I tried getting in touch with the friends I had made up North and nobody texted me back or emailed me back. I felt abandoned by my friends, by my church, by my heritage, by my family, by God. I had started to believe in God (after a long back-and-forth two years with my mentors, Kevin Tan and Victor Shia).</p>



<p>I started school at East Los Angeles College (ELAC). It felt wrong because nobody here was pursuing a PhD or a Master&#8217;s degree. It felt wrong because these were ordinary people and I felt like I belonged with a different crowd. It felt wrong because the student body was primarily Mexican. But it also felt familiar and comfortable. I decided to let go of my pride and learn to love being Mexican. I got on my knees and prayed to God to show me the way to live. A few days later, a Guatemalan skater approached my table by the food truck (where I was hosting my own &#8220;God Talk&#8221;) and he asked me if I wanted to study the Bible so I can learn the way to live. I was shocked because everything he was saying was almost the exact words I prayed in my prayer in my home alone on my knees. I studied the Bible for a few weeks and became a Christian when I was baptized on March 20, 2015 in Alhambra, CA.</p>



<p>It was at this time that I embraced being Mexican for the first time. I felt free and I was so excited to come home and tell my family that I had changed my life. But I went home to a big fight and they told me to take my Christianity to the trash. I felt rejected by my family but I had found a church family that would become my best friends. The skater kid, Jeff, became my best friend. He and I watched Spanish-language movies, TV shows, went on double dates with the sisters in the church, and I met his family. They helped me see that my view of family was wrong. I was wrong about my heritage. I was wrong about my direction in life. I was wrong to believe that I was an outsider. I was wrong and I was never more excited to be wrong! I started listening to <em>mariachi</em>, <em>corridos</em>, reggaeton, cumbia, salsa. I watched <em>Betty La Fea</em> and <em>La Fea Más Bella</em> reruns. I became an expert at making <em>enchiladas</em>. I absolutely wanted to embrace everything about how God made me. I enjoyed listening to Luis Miguel with my mom and would play it on my speaker and danced with her. There was still trouble at home but I was FREE! I finally felt comfortable in my own skin.</p>



<p>I visited Mexico City for the first time ever last month and I felt at home. I was there for a church missions conference and for my seminary school graduation. But I felt a connection to my heritage that I had never felt. My extended family met us there and I was on cloud nine walking through the streets of <em>El Cuerno</em> in the <em>Delegación Álvaro Obregón</em>. I met my dad&#8217;s side of the family for the first time and learned why they never visited. They are barely making it and are struggling to survive. I felt helpless and grateful for their generous hospitality. I felt like my family had welcomed me with a warm embrace and that I would always be welcome. I visited the pyramids at the Aztec-named city of <em>Teotihuacán</em>. I visited the Huey Teocalli dig site. I fell in love with my parents&#8217; home country. I practiced my Spanish to the point where my Mexican-residing side of the family told me that I did not have an American accent. I felt proud of that and felt proud of being Mexican. Eleven years ago, I just wished that my life would end. Today, I&#8217;m grateful to Matthew Liu for saving my life for such a time as this. THANK YOU!</p>



<p>Last night, I watched the Blue Beetle movie. I felt so invigorated that I was represented on the big screen that I overlooked some of the bad acting until one of the guys pointed it out. I saw the inside of the Reyes&#8217; house and felt like it was home. I took it personal when the villains challenged the protagonist. I felt that it was an attack on my home and my heritage. I cried and laughed during the movie. I felt simple joy afterwards. I felt represented as a Mexican American. I could never be more proud of my parents for making the BOLD and BRAVE move to the States.</p>



<p>#VivaMexico #MexicanAmerican #BlueBeetle</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/blue-beetle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
