<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/enjoy-life/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/maralkan-logo-favicon-3.png</url>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Priorities</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enjoy life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is the most important thing in your life?I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/">Priorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is the most important thing in your life?<span id="more-768"></span>I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at work. I woke up late, arrived at work late, and was clumsy in my servitude and customer service. I made my entire team struggle hard. And I was just struggling to keep up. It was only after work that I got to sit down, read my Bible, and pray. But that is one day of my life!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s crazy to think that our lives happen so quickly. We continue to strive and move forward but lately I&#8217;ve found myself wanting to stay. I wanted to retreat from the world of worry and from what causes me to stress. I felt like running away from my responsibilities and just floating on whatever. (Can anyone relate?) I just wanted to feel numb and live/work to get pleasure. But, this is a dark place! This kind of living leads to emptiness and suffering and ultimately, destructive behaviors that I was once enslaved to. And I couldn&#8217;t help but feel alone in all of it. But everyone goes through this. And I&#8217;m probably one of the best examples of how not to live life. It&#8217;s just not something that people talk about out loud.</p>
<p>Everyone knows that our lives are difficult. But, what do we make of it? Life has so much to offer! Thank God that we have a life to enjoy!</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;When times are good, be happy;<br />
but when times are bad, consider this:<br />
God has made the one<br />
as well as the other.<br />
Therefore, no one can discover<br />
anything about their future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 7:14</p></blockquote>
<p>Sure, we can have awesome days. But we all have those days that just don&#8217;t sit well with us. So I found myself reading this Scripture and found that the good and the bad, God allows. I need to learn something from everything! God is good. God is my Father. The bad can help me learn to improve my character.</p>
<p>So then, if I get caught up with all of the things in the middle of life, what then will I do? I can fill up my life with all of these fringe things that I can forget to appreciate what God has given to me.</p>
<p>I have:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kingdom of God</li>
<li>a physical family that loves me</li>
<li>great schooling</li>
<li>a decent job (it could be better, amen)</li>
</ul>
<p>As I fill my life, I must consider first, then, what is important. What is my purpose? What are my goals and dreams? What needs to come first?</p>
<p>Here are my answers:</p>
<ol>
<li>My purpose: to make disciples of all nations</li>
<li>My goal this year: to be a Bible Talk leader (a small group leader with a charge to evangelize a certain geographical region)</li>
<li>My dreams: to evangelize Japan and Mexico</li>
</ol>
<p>What is important?</p>
<ol>
<li>God (quiet times: singing to Him, praying, reading my Bible)</li>
<li>His Kingdom (spiritual family)</li>
<li>Family (physical family) &#8211;&gt; fun is included! -&gt; this is new to me</li>
<li>School</li>
<li>Work</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, on a practical level, this requires that I have a job that can finance these goals. It&#8217;s important that I never put my job over God, His Kingdom, or my family.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;So I commend the enjoyment of life, because there is nothing better for a person under the sun than to eat and drink and be glad. Then joy will accompany them in their toil all the days of the life God has given them under the sun. When I applied my mind to know wisdom and to observe the labor that is done on earth—people getting no sleep day or night—then I saw all that God has done. No one can comprehend what goes on under the sun. Despite all their efforts to search it out, no one can discover its meaning. Even if the wise claim they know, they cannot really comprehend it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 8:15-17</p></blockquote>
<p>So I will live by this: &#8220;Enjoy the lifestyle that God has set out for you&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;But everyone who hears these words of mine and does not put them into practice is like a foolish man who built his house on sand.&#8221;</p>
<p>Matthew 7:26</p></blockquote>
<p>I implore whoever reads this to also reevaluate their priorities. God is most important. It&#8217;s the most important question you can ask!</p>
<p>What is your purpose in life? Post in the comments! How do you want to change and live for God?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/">Priorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
