<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/category/notes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/maralkan-logo-favicon-3.png</url>
	<title>Sample Page - MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Priorities</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enjoy life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is the most important thing in your life?I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/">Priorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is the most important thing in your life?<span id="more-768"></span>I had to ask myself this question after a tough day at work. I woke up late, arrived at work late, and was clumsy in my servitude and customer service. I made my entire team struggle hard. And I was just struggling to keep up. It was only after work that I got to sit down, read my Bible, and pray. But that is one day of my life!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s crazy to think that our lives happen so quickly. We continue to strive and move forward but lately I&#8217;ve found myself wanting to stay. I wanted to retreat from the world of worry and from what causes me to stress. I felt like running away from my responsibilities and just floating on whatever. (Can anyone relate?) I just wanted to feel numb and live/work to get pleasure. But, this is a dark place! This kind of living leads to emptiness and suffering and ultimately, destructive behaviors that I was once enslaved to. And I couldn&#8217;t help but feel alone in all of it. But everyone goes through this. And I&#8217;m probably one of the best examples of how not to live life. It&#8217;s just not something that people talk about out loud.</p>
<p>Everyone knows that our lives are difficult. But, what do we make of it? Life has so much to offer! Thank God that we have a life to enjoy!</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;When times are good, be happy;<br />
but when times are bad, consider this:<br />
God has made the one<br />
as well as the other.<br />
Therefore, no one can discover<br />
anything about their future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 7:14</p></blockquote>
<p>Sure, we can have awesome days. But we all have those days that just don&#8217;t sit well with us. So I found myself reading this Scripture and found that the good and the bad, God allows. I need to learn something from everything! God is good. God is my Father. The bad can help me learn to improve my character.</p>
<p>So then, if I get caught up with all of the things in the middle of life, what then will I do? I can fill up my life with all of these fringe things that I can forget to appreciate what God has given to me.</p>
<p>I have:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kingdom of God</li>
<li>a physical family that loves me</li>
<li>great schooling</li>
<li>a decent job (it could be better, amen)</li>
</ul>
<p>As I fill my life, I must consider first, then, what is important. What is my purpose? What are my goals and dreams? What needs to come first?</p>
<p>Here are my answers:</p>
<ol>
<li>My purpose: to make disciples of all nations</li>
<li>My goal this year: to be a Bible Talk leader (a small group leader with a charge to evangelize a certain geographical region)</li>
<li>My dreams: to evangelize Japan and Mexico</li>
</ol>
<p>What is important?</p>
<ol>
<li>God (quiet times: singing to Him, praying, reading my Bible)</li>
<li>His Kingdom (spiritual family)</li>
<li>Family (physical family) &#8211;&gt; fun is included! -&gt; this is new to me</li>
<li>School</li>
<li>Work</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, on a practical level, this requires that I have a job that can finance these goals. It&#8217;s important that I never put my job over God, His Kingdom, or my family.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;So I commend the enjoyment of life, because there is nothing better for a person under the sun than to eat and drink and be glad. Then joy will accompany them in their toil all the days of the life God has given them under the sun. When I applied my mind to know wisdom and to observe the labor that is done on earth—people getting no sleep day or night—then I saw all that God has done. No one can comprehend what goes on under the sun. Despite all their efforts to search it out, no one can discover its meaning. Even if the wise claim they know, they cannot really comprehend it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ecclesiastes 8:15-17</p></blockquote>
<p>So I will live by this: &#8220;Enjoy the lifestyle that God has set out for you&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;But everyone who hears these words of mine and does not put them into practice is like a foolish man who built his house on sand.&#8221;</p>
<p>Matthew 7:26</p></blockquote>
<p>I implore whoever reads this to also reevaluate their priorities. God is most important. It&#8217;s the most important question you can ask!</p>
<p>What is your purpose in life? Post in the comments! How do you want to change and live for God?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/">Priorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/priorities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 01:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptable sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardened hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/">Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-699"></span></p>
<p>Today I read Jeremiah 6. A section dedicated entirely to explaining the hard-heartedness of the Israelite nation. I am just posting my notes.</p>
<p>The alarms aren&#8217;t sounding&#8230; God has warned his people of the consequences of their sin. Nobody listens. In fact, they shut their ears.</p>
<p>This is why the anger of God burns&#8230; They do not listen!</p>
<p>v14. To dress a wound improperly as though it were not serious is a very serious deceit. This hardening goes from the leaders to the people. If the leaders aren&#8217;t ashamed of their own conduct, the people won&#8217;t be ashamed either.&nbsp;This leads to a definitive hardening in the hearts of many.</p>
<p>v16. This is a crossroads. Every time I get discipling, it is a crossroads. I can choose to follow God&#8217;s way or my own way. God&#8217;s way: the good way, where I will find rest for my soul.</p>
<p>This is a case of discipline. When I was younger, my mom would often discipline me by threatening to make an example of me in front of my classmates. Man.. how I feared that! I feared that my deeds would be exposed. I feared that I would be exposed as some sort of incredibly immature guy. For a long time, I held on to this fear. And my mom never came through with the threats. I hardened myself to her and resisted her discipline. I&#8217;m very grateful that God did this for me. Later on, I would be disciplined by my brother in the church and, initially, I resisted and didn&#8217;t understand what was going on. And all that pains me now is that anyone with a hardened heart cannot please God. I couldn&#8217;t please my mom because I had started to dislike her and her discipline.</p>
<p>v20. Sacrifices that are fancy, much labor, or even great sacrifices aren&#8217;t pleasing to God and are, in fact, worship in vain when my heart is hard.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lord says:&nbsp;&#8220;These people come near to me with their mouth and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me.&nbsp;Their worship of me is based on merely human rules they have been taught&#8230;&#8221;&nbsp;— Isaiah 29:13 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>These sacrifices aren&#8217;t even acceptable!</p>
<p>v22. God will bring discipline! God warned his people and then disaster struck.</p>
<p>v26.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Suddenly the destroyer will come upon us.&#8221;&nbsp;— Jeremiah 6:26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>And this is the hand of God, not Satan. God disciplining and allowing his people to suffer the consequences so that the remnant can turn back to him.</p>
<p>When a metal caster is trying to extract metal from an ore, the ore must be refined. One must purify the metal. This purification involves a furnace that must increase in intensity until all impurities are gone. In this case, God had put his people into the furnace and the impurities were so deeply embedded that the metal would be nearly destroyed. And so the refining process was done in vain. And God rejected the ore.</p>
<h3>What do?</h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to have a hardened heart. I don&#8217;t want to have this kind of heart towards God. This makes the situation difficult for me and for everyone else around me. So why would I want to make this a difficult situation?</p>
<p>I have been in some difficult situations recently that involved a lot of sin on my part and sin on the part of some of my brothers. It was due to a character flaw in myself that happened to expose many hearts. All sin is bad. And these situations should never have happened. God isn&#8217;t planning on having me sin to refine other peoples&#8217; hearts. I must improve my character so that I won&#8217;t risk being a stumbling block to my brothers and sisters.</p>
<p>I have a new plan. Don&#8217;t try and look for flaws in someone else. Rather, just love everyone else and encourage as necessary. Prevent sin and make every effort to be at peace with everyone around me. This means that I must love everyone for who they are and not make prejudicial conclusions. I cannot pull my heart away from others. I must give my all.</p>
<p>At home. I must obey and honor my parents as I honor God. I will not sin if they ask me to (as they often ask me to do so). But I will honor them by obeying, giving, loving, and most of all, persevering in my life and doctrine (1 Timothy 4:16).</p>
<blockquote><p>And has just been said: &#8220;Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion.&#8221;&nbsp;— Hebrews 3:15 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/">Jerusalem Under Siege &#8211; A Hardened Nation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/jerusalem-under-siege-a-hardened-nation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doctrine</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 03:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As soon as it was night, the believers sent Paul and Silas away to Berea. On arriving there, they went&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/">Doctrine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-454"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>As soon as it was night, the believers sent Paul and Silas away to Berea. On arriving there, they went to the Jewish synagogue. Now the Berean Jews were of more noble character than those in Thessalonica, for they received the message with great eagerness and examined the Scriptures every day to see if what Paul said was true. As a result, many of them believed, as did also a number of prominent Greek women and many Greek men.&nbsp;— Acts 17:10-12 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>So there are many things that people can say about doctrines. They feel this about this Scripture and not that one. They feel that about the other Scripture. And you&#8217;re sitting there thinking, &#8220;where are you getting this from?&#8221; Or maybe you&#8217;re just sitting there agreeing without taking a second look.</p>
<p>I am part of a movement of churches that believes in studying the Scriptures for yourself so as to not get entangled by people&#8217;s opinions about any given topic (Acts 17:10-12). If there is a difference in &#8220;interpretation&#8221;, we bring it to light and we all get unified on what we believe. As such, there are many Scriptures that are very straightforward and do not require &#8220;interpretation&#8221;. Others, such as prophecies, require further study. An big example, is the study of the coming of the Kingdom of God. There are many prophecies about it in Isaiah, Daniel, Joel, and other prophets that came about during the time of the Babylonian exile. But good study reveals that all these prophecies are fulfilled in the book of Acts.</p>
<p>Then we have the topic of denominations. Why are there so many denominations of Christianity? Why is there so much division in a movement that is supposed to be one Church?</p>
<p>As a whole movement of Christianity, what makes us different from other religions? How are we different from Theraveda or Mahayana Buddhism? From Islam? From Judaism? What makes us different? How is our pursuit of salvation different from other religious traditions?</p>
<p>These are some of the thoughts and questions I was having. Whatever the cause of these questions, these are questions that shook and rocked my world recently. I did research into these religious traditions. I searched for answers that I thought I had already found. My lack of discipline in my quiet times with God had brought me to this point. Ultimately, I was about to give up on Christianity.</p>
<p>I related to Solomon&#8217;s thought process in Ecclesiastes:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Meaningless! Meaningless!&#8221; says the Teacher.&nbsp;&#8220;Utterly meaningless! Everything is meaningless.&#8221;&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 1:2 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote><p>Then I applied myself to the understanding of wisdom, and also of madness and folly, but I learned that this, too, is a chasing after the wind. For with much wisdom comes much sorrow; the more knowledge, the more grief.&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 1:17-18 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>Nothing meant anything to me. I was wondering whether things were really as they were. I lost myself in thought and missed class and work. I couldn&#8217;t figure things out. I was stuck in habitual sins but wondering whether or not these were really sins. I was questioning the nature of Creation, the nature of God, the heart, the soul, how connected an action is to the soul, how one can say that someone else is saved. And I realized that the more I searched for answers, the less satisfied I became with them. I decided that instead of searching for a revelation or some emotional experience, I would instead look at things as objectively as possible.</p>
<p>In Christianity, the life of Jesus and his relationship to God&nbsp;is the distinguishing trait of the religious tradition. In Buddhism, the teaching and reaching nirvana, the breaking of samsara is what is essential to the religious tradition. In Judaism, there is a hope and an expectation of God&#8217;s messiah to continue to rebuke the people of God. In Islam, there is the teaching and following of Mohammad. What makes me different?</p>
<p>At the age of 5, I was involved in an accident that sent me to the hospital. My dad was selling hot dogs in the streets of Downtown Los Angeles. Everyone loved his recipe and his business strategy. Soon hot dog stands like his sprang up all over Los Angeles. Everyone knew my dad. &#8220;Hot Dogs Adonai&#8221;, later renamed &#8220;Hot Dogs Jireh&#8221; was the name of my dad&#8217;s hot dog cart. It was during my aunt&#8217;s stay in our home.</p>
<p>We had humble circumstances. We weren&#8217;t living an extravagant life. But it was a life so much better than my parents had when they lived in Mexico. So on October 9th, 1999, my dad was selling his hot dogs just like every other day. My aunt was standing in the shade and she complained about the heat. My dad had a feeling that something was wrong. He smelled a gas leak. I was curious. He opened the bottom compartment to the cart and looked in. That&#8217;s when it happened. The gas made contact with the flame. I saw the flame shoot through the gas in the air and straight into the compartment my dad was looking into. The propane tank exploded in his face and the blast hit me all over my body. All I remember is the feeling of needles pinching and pulling my skin off. That&#8217;s the best way I can describe the pain I felt. I saw my mom rush over to me. My dad was slapping his face putting out flames. My mom lifted me onto a chair and was slapping my face with wet hands dousing the flames on my skin. I passed out. I remember haziness and an ambulance. I remember thinking it was so cool to be in an ambulance. The paramedics were putting needles into my arms and my mom was crying on the side. I passed out. I woke up at the hospital. They were taking me to a metal bin. They scrubbed my skin with steel wool. The 3rd degree burns were so deep that I felt as if the flames had engulfed me once more. Skin fell off.</p>
<p>I later found myself&nbsp;wrapped in white cloth in bed. I couldn&#8217;t move. I got one visitor, my pre-kindergarten teacher. I spent several months in recovery. There were many scary moments. There was a time that I flat-lined. They didn&#8217;t revive me and the medics&nbsp;gave up on me. And my mom protested. They were getting ready to cart me out and to bring in the next patient when I woke up asking why I hadn&#8217;t&nbsp;been taken to Griffith Park. Medics rushed in and out and some even&nbsp;covered their faces and ran out&nbsp;to the balcony and prayed to God (it was obvious). I moved back home and continued in recovery. Today I have no deep scars. I only have some small marks on my arms and hands that&nbsp;people do not notice unless I point it out.</p>
<p>I say all this because this is the first time I believed in God. This is not because of my parents indoctrinating me with their personal beliefs. It was of my own accord. I wanted to learn more.&nbsp;I was 5 years old and didn&#8217;t know how to appreciate life. So this fervor quickly died out.</p>
<p>When I began college, I began to question the idea of God. I wondered why I believed in God and had forgotten about this miracle that I had seen. It wasn&#8217;t long before I found myself in depression and stuck in ruts everywhere. I had no motivation and no zeal for learning. I just wanted to escape the world into&nbsp;fantasies. This led to many things. Sin after sin. It was then that I revisited my questions from childhood. I began to go to church at the request of one of my friends from college. Ultimately he felt that he didn&#8217;t need God. But I kept going. And I felt all the emotions and went to worship with a lot of people who had good hearts. But I was not taught to be a follower. I was not taught to be a worshiper in spirit and truth (John 4:23-24). I&nbsp;was later kicked out of school&nbsp;due to bad grades and my lack of understanding of how to manage life. I had to admit defeat to my parents and my family. My family had such high hopes for me and they were very disappointed. My parents, on the other hand, were very joyful to have me back home.</p>
<p>I began to attend a community college with the intent of returning to UC Berkeley. But my greatest challenge and time of learning came from my time at the community college. I learned to study the Bible and to teach the Bible. I learned what it meant to remain faithful and to be&nbsp;a pure man for God. It&#8217;s when I was baptized and began discipleship.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also the time that I&nbsp;began to try and learn wisdom and understanding from other cultures and other peoples. Specifically, I was interested in Japanese culture and religious philosophy. But that led me to more questioning. I was again caught up in&nbsp;trying to escape reality. Life got difficult. I watched more anime. I read other books and not my Bible. I watched all sorts of dramas that didn&#8217;t help me grow. Slowly I began to poison my thinking and to fall away in my heart.</p>
<p>So about going with the correct doctrine, I decided to look at my questions. After one month of questioning with no research and no effort made into reconciling with God, I went back to the Bible. I decided to pray to God once more.</p>
<p>I believe in a soul I believe that Jesus is God. I considered the psychoanalyses of Jesus and determined that he wasn&#8217;t just some crazy guy claiming to be God. He wasn&#8217;t lying. People have waged wars and have lost their lives for this belief. Countless martyrs have battled these other philosophies and found them fruitless. How can you know that you&#8217;ve lived before and have had past lives? I can&#8217;t really know. How can you know what there is after this life? I don&#8217;t know. Maybe it&#8217;s emptiness and maybe it&#8217;s another life. But I know that there is a man who claimed to be God and died for all. This act of love is&nbsp;a greater truth than anything I&#8217;ve ever seen.</p>
<p>If God so loved the world, and many people claim to be Christian, why is there so much hatred and sin in the world? They haven&#8217;t repented of their sins. They falsely call themselves Christian. They falsely claim to love others. But at the same time, there are people who are genuinely disciples of Christ. And can be very misunderstood because of one action where they let their sinful nature get the best of them. There is only what we know and what we can know. The rest is faith. We walk in faith. I choose this path of faith because it&#8217;s what&nbsp;makes the most sense. Buddhist teachings are not quite there.&nbsp;I can actually say that someone died for me. The Buddha didn&#8217;t die for me. He didn&#8217;t even want to share his great revelation. He did it anyway but he died. He will not come back and rescue. Even the Mahayana branch that refuses to fully achieve nirvana cannot say that they love as Jesus Christ did. Islam&nbsp;describes Jesus as a greater prophet than Mohammad. I am still learning. But learning without God is meaningless. Nobody&nbsp;will benefit. And working for others&nbsp;who do not understand what things are for is pointless. My purpose is simply to live for God. I repented of all my sins. I have considered that Creation alone is not the divine reality. Cause and effect&nbsp;is real. God is real.</p>
<blockquote><p>Now all has been heard; here is the conclusion of the matter: Fear God and keep his commandments, for this is the duty of all mankind. For God will bring every deed into judgment, including every hidden thing, whether it is good or evil.&nbsp;— Ecclesiastes 12:13-14 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/">Doctrine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/doctrine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grace</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 03:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/">Grace</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift of God — Ephesians 2:8</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span id="more-407"></span>I&#8217;ve heard it so many times. Many people like to say, &#8220;by grace we have been saved&#8221;. But I had to ask myself the question. What does grace mean? Why are there so many doctrines that differ on the concept of salvation by grace? Why do people say that they want to continue sinning so that God can have more grace?</p>
<p>I was recently able to share a bit of my testimony in front of my church. It was challenging to say the least. Not the part about speaking in front of the crowd, but the part about being sincere and being vulnerable to the point of shedding a tear or two.</p>
<p>This is what I shared:</p>
<p>When I think of the cross, I think grace. I don&#8217;t know about you, but I am a messed up person. There are so many things that I&#8217;d like to claim that I can do well. I have a knack for working with computers, learning languages, for learning and expressing myself clearly. Cool! None of it matters&#8230;</p>
<p>Turn with me to Ephesians 2.</p>
<blockquote><p>As for you, you were <strong>dead</strong> in your transgressions and sins, in which you used to live when you followed the ways of this world and of the ruler of the kingdom of the air, the spirit who is now at work in those who are disobedient. All of us also lived among them at one time, gratifying the cravings of our flesh and following its desires and thoughts. Like the rest, we were by nature deserving of wrath. But because of his great love for us, God, who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions—it is by grace you have been saved. And God raised us up with Christ and seated us with him in the heavenly realms in Christ Jesus, in order that in the coming ages he might show the incomparable riches of his grace, expressed in his kindness to us in Christ Jesus. For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the <strong>gift of God</strong>— not by works, so that no one can boast. For we are God’s handiwork, created in Christ Jesus <strong>to do good works</strong>, which God prepared in advance for us to do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I reflected on this passage. I was dead in my transgressions and sins. I was the kind of guy that nobody would hang around with. I have messed up so many times in my life, it&#8217;s impossible to say that <em>I&#8217;m</em> not a sinner.</p>
<p>When I was in high school, I had so much pride in myself! I used to think that I was the smartest at school. I would honestly believe that I was smarter than all of the students there. I joined the Academic Decathlon in order to fulfill my desire to be glorified. I thought that I would win medals and awards and scholarships and get so much glory. I was wrong. All I did was push people away. People who genuinely wanted to be my friends, I would punch them and tell them that they were worthless and not worth my time. Others I didn&#8217;t have the patience for. I met a guy who was so humble and so grateful that I even spoke to him. And I pushed him away too. I had no friends. And I had the illusion that my teacher was my friend. Just because he kept telling me that I was smart and &#8220;going places&#8221;. I delighted to think that the people who would bully me in middle school would be my employees one day or that I would make them suffer for what they did to me. I thought that by proving my parents wrong I would somehow get them to say that they were proud of me. They often told me so. But I felt nothing when they did say it. Because I felt the emptiness of vain glory. I hurt people and didn&#8217;t care. But I couldn&#8217;t figure out why I was so empty. I didn&#8217;t get <em>any</em> medals at the end of the competition. I cried that day. I was bitter at everyone. Everyone had a smile on their face. Everyone had worked hard and was friends with someone else. Everyone had the dream life.</p>
<p>Moving forward, I got into UC Berkeley. Hooray! [sarcasm]. I became worse. But now that I really didn&#8217;t know anyone, I felt the loneliness. My parents and family were not there anymore. I began to see how other students would sabotage each other&#8217;s work in order to be the top of the class. I began to see so much darkness in the world. I thought that I had it going and I had nothing. I messed up. I messed up thinking that I could go on living in impurity, insecurity, etc. I was not the smartest guy anymore. Everyone had equal or greater capacity. Mostly greater capacity. I was humbled out. I lost so much faith in my own ability. I thought that I had nothing to bring to this world. I wanted to leave the world.</p>
<p>The evening that I would go ahead with that plan, one of the guys who lived on the same floor as I did in the dorms literally had to drag me out of my room in order to get me to come to church. Now, it wasn&#8217;t the church that would tell me how to get saved, but it was definitely a wake-up call. I was raised in a religious household. I was sick of God. But this time, I resonated with the message of hope. I had lived a life of sin. I was heartless, prideful, insecure, impure, hateful, dissensuous, immoral, and worst of all, guilty.</p>
<p>I studied the Bible and started seeking God with all my heart. And on March 20, 2015, I was baptized for the forgiveness of my sins. I made a decision to live my life as a disciple of Christ. Did I stop sinning the way I did? I tried my best not to sin, but I had to learn and unlearn at the same time. I would argue with people about who was right about the Bible and who wasn&#8217;t. I made mistake after mistake after mistake. I do not deserve forgiveness. And yet, I have forgiveness. I do not deserve the love of God and yet I have it. I do not deserve the death of Christ, and yet He has risen. Grace simply means that God had mercy. God had mercy on a hopeless sinner like myself. God gave it all for me. Why should I continue sinning? And yet I continue to sin. However, it is most definitely <strong><em>not</em></strong> a license for me to sin.</p>
<p>But I still have one message of hope. As I think of the cross, I think of Romans 5:8</p>
<blockquote><p>But God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have been made alive in Christ. I am no longer subject to the pain of sin. I am no longer defined by my sin. I have hope! And I would be selfish and heartless not to share this hope with someone else.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/">Grace</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/grace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to God</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/">Letter to God</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-390"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace. And be thankful. Let the message of Christ dwell among you richly as you teach and admonish one another with all wisdom through psalms, hymns, and songs from the Spirit, singing to God with gratitude in your hearts. And whatever you do, whether in word or deed, do it all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. — Colossians 3:15-17</p></blockquote>
<p>We were charged to write a letter to God in order to connect with God at a more personal level and to be more grateful for what He has done in our lives. As grateful followers/disciples, we can go out and actually evangelize this world. Gratitude is something that I&#8217;ve noticed brings a lot of repentance and change in people. No matter where they come from.</p>
<p>I include my letter here.</p>
<p>Dear Dad,</p>
<p>I am very glad that I can talk to you this morning. Thank you for the privilege of being able to write this letter to you. Thank you God for always being there to bring in a new day. You keep the stars in their current trajectories. You keep the sun in it&#8217;s place. You allow the Earth to continue rotating on it&#8217;s axis at the particular angle that it is tilted at. You stand at eternity radiating peace, love, patience, kindness, joy.</p>
<p>I am nothing like you God. And yet you cared enough to make man in your image. Something that we, as your creations, are unable to do. We cannot create another person from scratch. And if we do, it&#8217;s with your materials. We can&#8217;t create our atoms from scratch. We can&#8217;t do anything without you, God.</p>
<p>I was listening to some songs where the singer expresses lots of gratitude towards their best friend. And these are people who don&#8217;t really know you, God! How can I say that I&#8217;ve been grateful to you? Please forgive me for being so ungrateful to you. I haven&#8217;t even stopped to think about how much you&#8217;ve done for me for quite a while, now. Thank you God for always being there for me. You were there when I was burned and in the hospital. When I cried out in prayer and the nurses and doctors were telling my mom to shut me up. And yet they witnessed a miracle in front of their eyes. I should not even be alive if it weren&#8217;t for you. Yet again, when I&#8217;ve been in danger multiple times in my life. Running in the streets of Downtown Oakland in the night, fearing that I would be jumped or taken hostage by someone. When you protected me from many more things. I&#8217;ve had my life placed in so many dangerous situations and yet I continue to live. Thank you God for not giving up on me.</p>
<p>There have been times when I trust people more than I trusted you. Primarily, it was before I was a disciple. But even as a disciple, I&#8217;ve placed my trust in people. When it was revealed, I was broken and realized that it was you that I needed, not the love of someone else. I was trying to be in a situation where I felt loved by someone here on earth. But then I realized that I&#8217;m not trying to store up treasures for myself here on earth. Why was I trying to do that? I didn&#8217;t trust you, God. But I realize now that you were always there.</p>
<p>You were there when I felt so discouraged and lonely in Berkeley. I have a feeling you were probably whispering in my ear, telling me to seek after you. To not follow through with the desires to end it all. I didn&#8217;t end it all. I ended up at the TSF. Although it wasn&#8217;t the right place to be at, it was the right place at the right time. You set up the times and places for everyone. For my family. For myself. You are the one who made it all possible. You kept me alive. You allowed me to experience the world as I did. I was betrayed, trusted, betrayed again. And I saw the hearts of people turn away from me. And yet I didn&#8217;t learn my lesson. I didn&#8217;t understand that I was still trusting in men. Even for a while as a disciple, I still felt led by people and not by you. But you were still there. You were faithful even though I was not.</p>
<p>You also gave me the family that I have today. They love me. And there are times when I am ungrateful towards them. I yell at them, letting them know that I&#8217;m a person as well (at least, in my mind). I thought that by yelling at them I would stop them from yelling at me. (haha I was so wrong). When I thought that they were against me because they did not let me do the Academic Decathlon, I was extremely rebellious. And yet, you allowed that to happen. You allowed me to go to Sam K. and let him know that he&#8217;s better than my parents. I sincerely thought he was looking out for me more than my own parents were. I still have confusion about that. I don&#8217;t understand what my parents motives were. I don&#8217;t understand Sam&#8217;s motivations. All I know is that my motivations were selfish. I had an intense selfish ambition. I wanted to feel honored and respected by everyone else. I wanted to hear that I was better than someone else. And I was very disappointed when I didn&#8217;t get it. And God, you obviously had a hand in that. My strong suit was supposed to be math. And I was failing at it. I understood how to do it. But, in practice, I couldn&#8217;t do it under pressure.</p>
<p>You gave me talent. There are many times that I&#8217;m afraid of saying that I can do things because I don&#8217;t want to be prideful. And by feeling that, I feel insecure. I want to be called humble. So paradoxical&#8230; and yet again, signs of pride. I really have nothing to bring to the table but the things that you&#8217;ve given me. I only ask that you allow me to use these talents to glorify you. Allow me to reach out with this. I can reach a community that is not often reached. I have access to some of the greatest minds, according to the wisdom of the world. And yet, I can sometimes let it slip. I feel lazy. I don&#8217;t feel like studying. I don&#8217;t feel like trying to glorify you. But you are still there.</p>
<p>Dad, you made me to glorify you and do your work. Thank you for giving me a new purpose for my life. Thank you for giving me friends who care. Thank you for allowing me to be in your kingdom. Thank you for allowing me to come clean to you. Thank you for your forgiveness.</p>
<p>Thank you, Jesus for your sacrifice. Thank you that because you denied yourself, I don&#8217;t have to suffer for eternity. Thank you that you&#8217;ve given me eyesight, hearing, language, normalcy in brain habit. Thank you for giving me the brothers and sister that I have. Thank you for testing my faith, that it may be refined by fire. Thank you for placing me in charge of websites. Thank you for placing me under Jeff and Jovanny. Thank you for teaching me your words. Thank you for answering my prayers with getting to know you. Thank you for bringing in so many souls. Thank you for my brothers and sisters around the world. Thank you for your love. Thank you for everything. Thank you for the job that I have. Thank you for allowing me to share with my co-workers alongside a fellow brother and disciple. Thank you for giving me clothing to wear. Thank you for giving me good to eat. Thank you for giving me a new computer. Thank you for giving me what I need. Thank you for giving me people to lead. I&#8217;m unworthy of receiving anything. I&#8217;m like the prodigal son. I don&#8217;t deserve it. I&#8217;m like the other soon, feeling like I deserve something that I really don&#8217;t. Thank you God.</p>
<p>You are awesome in everything that you do. You are incredible. You work great miracles in our day and age. You are patient, kind, loving, generous, faithful.</p>
<p>You gave it all for me. Why can&#8217;t I give it all to you? God, give me strength to carry on your dream. Give me strength to do your will when I cannot. All things come from you. All things are made by you.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s so much more that I can pray about as well. Brothers and sisters around the world are struggling. Some are sick some are not. People in this world are suffering because of sin. Help them get closer to you. Give them what they need to seek you. For the workers in the harvest. Lord send me. Here I am Lord. Send me.</p>
<p>I very well would like to go to Japan. I would very much like to share with souls who need saving from their destructive worldview. Sometimes it&#8217;s mind boggling to me to see that people want yo believe in ghosts and not in you. People want yo believe in death, in demons, in statues, in money. People understand these things at the intellectual level but do not practice them. I saw that at bible talk. A woman tried to defend her independence from you. I could hear pride come out.</p>
<p>Thanks for all that you do!</p>
<p>-Your son,<br />
Marvin Alcántara</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/">Letter to God</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/letter-to-god/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Excellent Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excellent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/">Excellent Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-363"></span>Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just a superficial remedy. He heals completely and thoroughly, leaving no blemish behind.</p>
<p>In Mark 7, Jesus healed a deaf and mute man. Now, being sensitive to those who are deaf and mute, this is something that, according to the hearing world, is considered a disease of some sort. But Jesus did something incredible.</p>
<blockquote><p>Then Jesus left the vicinity of Tyre and went through Sidon, down to the Sea of Galilee and into the region of the Decapolis. There some people brought to him a man who was deaf and could hardly talk, and they begged Jesus to place his hand on him.</p>
<p>After he took him aside, away from the crowd, Jesus put his fingers into the man’s ears. Then he spit and touched the man’s tongue. He looked up to heaven and with a deep sigh said to him, “Ephphatha!” (which means “Be opened!”). At this, the man’s ears were opened, his tongue was loosened and he began to speak plainly.</p>
<p>Jesus commanded them not to tell anyone. But the more he did so, the more they kept talking about it. People were overwhelmed with amazement. “He has done everything well,” they said. “He even makes the deaf hear and the mute speak.” — Mark 7:31-37 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>Today, modern procedures for someone to hear requires Deaf people to have an intrusive device that looks obvious on them. These devices, can be very painful experiences to those who have lived deaf lives. I&#8217;ve heard many accounts of these hearing aids comparing the sudden influx of noise to a massive train wreck playing in our ears at volume levels too intense for us to bear. Deaf people with hearing aids must go through a lot in order to be part of the hearing world. Again, these hearing aids cause massive &#8220;migraine&#8221; headaches that are too much to bear.</p>
<p>But Jesus healed a man at a time when this was not even a possibility in people&#8217;s minds. Jesus installed a language into a man&#8217;s mind. He cured a man of would-be headaches and even have the man muscle memory for the tongue, that he would be able to speak possibly as if he had spoken the language his whole life. That&#8217;s amazing!</p>
<p>My major in school is cognitive science. Because of it, I&#8217;m able to appreciate the fact that this man had to receive a sudden influx of information into his brain, had to have many neural pathways changed, and he needed to have nerve paths hardened before Jesus&#8217;s fingers left the man&#8217;s ears. And that&#8217;s not even touching the fact that the man&#8217;s ears are now sensitive to sound. The cochlea, the inner ear, is now able to perceive sound the way it is supposed to. This man was also <em>probably</em> able to communicate the wonders of God and Jesus in sign language as well! This was definitely a contribution to the world evangelization described in the book of Acts. I say the word &#8220;probably&#8221; with caution; it&#8217;s not in the Bible!</p>
<p>Now, Jesus loved this man and healed him completely. I now ask myself this question&#8230; How do I love others? Do I love someone &#8220;just enough&#8221;? Or do I go out of my way to love my brothers, sisters, and those outside? I had a conversation with a fellow student regarding the Catholic faith. We differed on the basis that I hold the Bible to be the ultimate and final authority in all things related to God and my life. But he holds the Church to be the final authority and the Bible is merely a book of guidelines. We differ and I don&#8217;t hold it against him. But I do tell him to challenge his way of thinking. This is the primary way by which false doctrines came into the church. This is the main reason why so many people think they&#8217;re doing all things right. This is why people believe that they can be saved with a simple prayer. It&#8217;s because churches have subjected the Bible to be merely a book of guidelines. It&#8217;s not the Word of God. It&#8217;s instead just a set of inspired writings that have man&#8217;s intentions written all over them. He thinks that one receives salvation through the Eucharist tradition of the Catholic church.</p>
<p>Regardless of how much I know, I still will not be able to win him over using knowledge of the Scriptures. It&#8217;s loving excellently as Jesus did. It&#8217;s dying to myself and not getting into quarrels about knowledge. It&#8217;s truly living a pure life. It&#8217;s taking care of my life and my doctrine.</p>
<blockquote><p><sup>16</sup> Watch your life and doctrine closely. Persevere in them, because if you do, you will save both yourself and your hearers. — 1 Timothy 4:16</p></blockquote>
<p>And also:</p>
<blockquote><p>1 Jesus knew that the Father had put all things under his power, and that he had come from God and was returning to God; so he got up from the meal, took off his outer clothing, and wrapped a towel around his waist. After that, he poured water into a basin and began to wash his disciples’ feet, drying them with the towel that was wrapped around him.</p>
<p>He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, “Lord, are you going to wash my feet?”</p>
<p>Jesus replied, “You do not realize now what I am doing, but later you will understand.”</p>
<p>“No,” said Peter, “you shall never wash my feet.”</p>
<p>Jesus answered, “Unless I wash you, you have no part with me.”</p>
<p>“Then, Lord,” Simon Peter replied, “not just my feet but my hands and my head as well!”</p>
<p>12 When he had finished washing their feet, he put on his clothes and returned to his place. “Do you understand what I have done for you?” he asked them. “You call me ‘Teacher’ and ‘Lord,’ and rightly so, for that is what I am. Now that I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also should wash one another’s feet. I have set you an example that you should do as I have done for you. Very truly I tell you, no servant is greater than his master, nor is a messenger greater than the one who sent him. Now that you know these things, you will be blessed if you do them.” — John 13:1-9, 12-17 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Just as Jesus loved, so I should love. There are times when I don&#8217;t feel like loving my brother. But how can I love God, who I can&#8217;t see, if I can&#8217;t love my brother, who I can see? Jesus loved excellently. I will do so as well.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">-M</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/">Excellent Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Being Faithful</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 01:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#8217;m continuing to read Mark&#8217;s account of the ministry of Jesus. I think it&#8217;s interesting how Jesus had a&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/">Being Faithful</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-240"></span>Today, I&#8217;m continuing to read Mark&#8217;s account of the ministry of Jesus. I think it&#8217;s interesting how Jesus had a heart to help everyone but wanted to remain on the down low until it was his time. Curiously, there&#8217;s the aspect of Jesus that many people can often overlook.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Very early in the morning, while it was still dark, Jesus got up, left the house and went off to a solitary place, where <strong>he prayed</strong>. Simon and his companions went to look for him, and when they found him, they exclaimed: “Everyone is looking for you!” Jesus replied, “Let us go somewhere else—to the nearby villages—so I can preach there also. <strong>That is why I have come</strong>.” So he traveled throughout Galilee, preaching in their synagogues and driving out demons. — Mark 1:35-39 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Prayer and Reading</h3>
<p>Jesus had a daily relationship with God. As I learn to imitate Christ, I must have a daily relationship with God. How can I be best friends with someone if I don&#8217;t talk to them? How can I say I love God if I don&#8217;t talk to him or read his Word? Again, I can reference Romans 10:17 NIV.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">Consequently, faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the <strong>word about Christ</strong>. — Romans 10:17 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Jesus had a daily relationship with God. But another thing to note, is that he always had time with God before he did anything throughout the day. We don&#8217;t have his prayer but it&#8217;s probably for strength. Why would anyone want to love people who are only interested in you because you provide some sort of advantage and no real friendship? Jesus prayed and then he decided to go elsewhere so that others may hear his preaching. So far, the only thing we know is that he has preached about the coming of the kingdom of God. And since the kingdom of God has come near, people must repent and believe that it is good news!</p>
<p>But what does this message that he preaches have to do with Christ? In a future post, I will talk about the kingdom of God in further detail. But it leaves me with obvious impression that Jesus is not preaching about himself. He is preaching about something important that is to come and is very near.</p>
<h3>Purpose</h3>
<p>When Jesus told his first disciples to follow him, he talked to fishermen with words that they knew about. He used their profession to explain to them that he has a new purpose for them. Now, these are his disciples. Today, people think that a disciple is so much more than a Christian. A Christian, for some reason, means that you go to church and have some sort of intellectual belief in a supernatural being that he/she calls God. But a disciple is a follower, a student, a friend, an apprentice. How are they different? Is a disciple more faithful than a Christian? Is a Christian then, some term that you can use freely to say that you believe in a supernatural being?</p>
<p>In the Greek, χριστιανους is the word used in the 1550 Stephanus New Testament. This word means &#8220;follower of Christ&#8221; or, depending on the translation, &#8220;little Christ&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>Then Barnabas went to Tarsus to look for Saul, and when he found him, he brought him to Antioch. So for a whole year Barnabas and Saul met with the church and taught great numbers of people. The <strong>disciples</strong> were called <strong>Christians</strong> first at Antioch. — Acts 11:25-26 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>All of the followers of Christ were disciples. Nobody ever dared to call himself a Christian. It was a derogatory term used to condemn people. So what happened that suddenly people are proud to call themselves &#8220;Christian&#8221; but not &#8220;disciples&#8221;? Is the word &#8220;disciple&#8221; too strong? They&#8217;re the same thing! So, if you&#8217;re still thinking that you&#8217;re one of these but not the other, you might need to check yourself. If you&#8217;re not a &#8220;disciple&#8221;, you&#8217;re not being a real Christian.</p>
<p>Anyway, Jesus gave his disciples a new purpose for their lives. Now, their purpose in life is to go out and &#8220;fish for people&#8221;. Interestingly, this is Jesus&#8217; first and last teaching according to Matthew and Mark just before his ascension to his disciples. Therefore it must hold some significance. Jesus gave his disciples a purpose to their lives. Now, Jesus taught everyone the same things. Why would that teaching change for me? I&#8217;m not an &#8220;apostle&#8221;! Does that make me exempt from Jesus&#8217; teaching? Is talking to someone too hard? Faith is not about having an intellectual idea that God exists. One doesn&#8217;t say that he/she has faith that a chair will not break and then proceed to never sit on it! If somebody has faith that a chair will not break when he/she sits on it, he/she will sit on it. If I have faith that Jesus is God, then I must do something about it!</p>
<p>I have to ask myself: am I about my purpose as a disciple of Christ? Since I go to school and have a job, is my purpose about my school, career, job, family? Is my purpose to please God or please myself?</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">Then Jesus came to them and said, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age.” — Matthew 28:18-20 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/">Being Faithful</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/being-faithful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unconditional Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconditional love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/">Unconditional Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-189"></span>I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night that I need to have more faith to be able to be strong in all situations. (Romans 10:17 NIV)</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">And a voice came from heaven: &#8220;You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased.&#8221; — Mark 1:11 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">A Christian is a follower of Jesus. Therefore, an imitator of Jesus. God was well pleased with Jesus. Therefore, as I imitate Christ, God will be pleased with me just as Jesus pleased him in his time. What&#8217;s crazy is that God has long encouraged prophets to remain steadfast and to know his heart. But this time it was different. This time, God was pleased with Jesus before he had started his ministry! Already, this distinguishes Jesus from all of the prophets.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The question here is, how do I imitate Christ? Simple, I must learn what Jesus did and taught. How do I learn that? I can&#8217;t rely on anyone to teach me. I must do it for myself. It&#8217;s my personal relationship with God.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">So then, what are the teachings of Jesus? I guess I&#8217;m going to learn more and more as I continue to read the Bible.</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">Application for Today</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">Today, it seems, I will have to follow the example of Christ.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Love must be sincere.</strong> Hate what is evil; cling to what is good. <strong>Be devoted to one another in love. Honor one another above yourselves.</strong> Never be lacking in zeal, but keep your spiritual fervor, serving the Lord. Be joyful in hope, patient in affliction, faithful in prayer. Share with the Lord’s people who are in need. Practice hospitality.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Bless those who persecute you; bless and do not curse. Rejoice with those who rejoice; mourn with those who mourn. Live in harmony with one another. Do not be proud, but be willing to associate with people of low position. Do not be conceited.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Do not repay anyone evil for evil. Be careful to do what is right in the eyes of everyone. <strong>If it is possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone.</strong> Do not take revenge, my dear friends, but leave room for God’s wrath, for it is written: “It is mine to avenge; I will repay,” says the Lord. On the contrary:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">“If your enemy is hungry, feed him;<br />
if he is thirsty, give him something to drink.<br />
In doing this, you will heap burning coals on his head.”<br />
Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good. — Romans 12:9-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">and</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">We love because he first loved us. Whoever claims to love God yet hates a brother or sister is a <strong>liar</strong>. For whoever does not love their brother and sister, whom they have seen, <strong>cannot love God</strong>, whom they have not seen. And <strong>he has given us this command</strong>: Anyone who loves God must also love their brother and sister. — 1 John 4:19-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Christ taught many times throughout his time on earth and through his apostles&#8217; writings that we must have love for one another. I can imitate Christ by having love for my brothers (<em>adelphoi</em> means brothers and sisters). How can I love my brothers? I can definitely start by changing my character. So many times, I thought that everyone else had to change because I was doing everything right. I love people, I give sacrificially, I do more things (in my opinion) than others. But that doesn&#8217;t make me righteous. When someone ignores me I get butthurt and I tend to pull away my love because I think it&#8217;s not worth it to love a person who will not appreciate my love. But Christ commands us to love as he did. He loved despite the rejection of the apostles when he was turned in to the authorities. He loved always. So I must also always love even in the face of rejection. That way, I will overcome evil with good. That way I can imitate Christ and live a life pleasing to God.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/">Unconditional Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Godly Sorrow</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[godly sorrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the struggle against sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>God pours out his heart on all the people of Israel because they constantly forsake him and Jeremiah (or who&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/">Godly Sorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-104"></span>God pours out his heart on all the people of Israel because they constantly forsake him and Jeremiah (or who knows??) records in the second chapter. Now that I read it, I feel it applies to me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">&#8220;&#8230; Has a nation ever changed its gods? (Yet they are not gods at all.)<br />
But my people have exchanged their glorious God for worthless idols.<br />
Be appalled at this, you heavens, and shudder with great horror,” declares the Lord.<br />
“My people have committed two sins: They have forsaken me, the spring of living water, and have dug their own cisterns, broken cisterns that cannot hold water. &#8230;&#8221; — Jeremiah 2:11-13 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">It is not a secret that we are sinners. That I am a sinner. There are times when I continue to do the same thing over and over again. It&#8217;s not that I can&#8217;t control it&#8230; It&#8217;s that I deliberately want to sin. There&#8217;s no excuse where I can say that I accidentally sinned (though, it does happen when I unintentionally hurt someone else). The point is, I feel like God is telling me that I am like Israel, exchanging the glory of God for temporary pleasures or for lies.</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">What do?</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">So what do I do about it? James 5 tells me that I must confess my sins to another disciple and have him pray for me that I may be healed. And I must reciprocate to anyone who confesses their sins to me. But more than that, I must have godly sorrow.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death. See what this godly sorrow has produced in you: what earnestness, what eagerness to clear yourselves, what indignation, what alarm, what longing, what concern, what readiness to see justice done. At every point you have proved yourselves to be innocent in this matter. So even though I wrote to you, it was neither on account of the one who did the wrong nor on account of the injured party, but rather that before God you could see for yourselves how devoted to us you are. — 2 Corinthians 7:10-12 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Paul talks about the difference between feeling guilty about sin and actually doing something about it. Whenever I&#8217;m in sin, I tend to drop into worldly sorrow and beat myself up, regretting the past. It&#8217;s very difficult to get into a godly sorrow. Every time this happens, I seem to grasp a bit more that I cannot understand why God would forgive me. And yet, God forgives. He extended forgiveness to the Israelites through repentance. Unfortunately, they didn&#8217;t repent and change their ways. Seeing that I have the opportunity to repent fully of my sins, I must take that chance and fully repent.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">What does that look like?</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">Repentance</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">Repentance is turning away from something in the opposite direction. So if I were to repent of going to my friend&#8217;s house, I would simply turn around and go back to my house. Simple concept. Easier said than done.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">For myself, there are certain things that I can absolutely get rid of so that I may have greater self-control. Things such as my media consumption at home can be limited in various ways. Other things such as my association with people who like to do things that I once loved to do. Of course, I&#8217;m not going to completely run someone off. But I can move away from them and protect my purity and good character (as if I had great character&#8230;). Will that solve my problems? No. I must constantly be in prayer about these things. I really am unable to do this alone. That&#8217;s why I rely on my brothers and sisters in the faith. My brothers especially help me stay focused and pure. My sisters help me stay humble every time anything comes out of my mouth.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Will I do it? Definitely. Will I forsake God like the Israelites did for some temporary pleasures? No. I cannot betray God like that. I cannot leave the Kingdom of God for the World!!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">You&#8217;re probably reading this and are wondering why I would ever post something so publicly vulnerable on the Internet. I don&#8217;t mind people knowing my life. I leave this so that someone can maybe gain something from it. Maybe someone can come to know that there is hope in life. Life is not just your job and your school. It&#8217;s more than your mom, dad, brothers, and sisters. There is a God!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/">Godly Sorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/godly-sorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faithfulness, Or Lack Thereof</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 03:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s quiet time reading was pretty interesting. I read Jeremiah 2 and expected to see the sin of Israel that&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/">Faithfulness, Or Lack Thereof</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-81"></span>Today&#8217;s quiet time reading was pretty interesting. I read Jeremiah 2 and expected to see the sin of Israel that brought it into ruin. But I didn&#8217;t expect it to be worse. Jeremiah 2 begins to explain how God feels when we sin against him. This was flat convicting.</p>
<p>I realize more and more the reality of the people forsaking God. Today, this world goes to great lengths to declare God as a myth or as some fairy tale made up to satisfy the needs of a weak people.</p>
<p>But myths aside, nobody can prove or disprove God. It is up to the person whether or not they want to believe in whatever they want to believe. So when a person comes to acknowledge the existence of God, they may at first be super excited! I mean&#8230; who wouldn&#8217;t? The answer to a question so complex as this is definitely satisfying. But nonetheless it requires faith.</p>
<p>Faith is something that the Jews lacked throughout their history. Jeremiah comes at the dawn of the darkest time in Jewish history. Jeremiah is young and is not confident in the words of God. But regardless, Jeremiah has enough faith to confront Israel in its lack of commitment towards God.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">The word of the Lord came to me: <span id="en-NIV-18968">“Go and proclaim in the hearing of Jerusalem:</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">“This is what the Lord says:</p>
<div style="text-align:left;">
<p>“‘I remember the devotion of your youth,<br />
how as a bride you loved me<br />
and followed me through the wilderness,<br />
through a land not sown.<br />
<span id="en-NIV-18969">Israel was holy to the Lord,</span><br />
the firstfruits of his harvest;<br />
all who devoured her were held guilty,<br />
and disaster overtook them,’”<br />
declares the Lord.</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align:left;">
<p><span id="en-NIV-18970">Hear the word of the Lord, you descendants of Jacob,</span><br />
all you clans of Israel.</p>
</div>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span id="en-NIV-18971">This is what the Lord says:</span></p>
<div>
<p style="text-align:left;">“What fault did your ancestors find in me,<br />
that they strayed so far from me?<br />
They followed worthless idols<br />
and became worthless themselves. — Jeremiah 2:1-5 NIV</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<div class="poetry top-05">
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">There are a couple of points to make here. The Jews were once devoted to God! They had a strong faith and they held their own (with God&#8217;s help) against other kingdoms. The Israelites, at this point, were people who were true followers of God. But what happened? That&#8217;s exactly the question that God asks the Israelites in verse 5. What happened?</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">Today, the modern Christian is very hard to respect. In the United States, the average &#8220;Christian&#8221; goes to church on Sundays. But is that all there is to devoting one&#8217;s life to God? There are so many churches today that preach that all you have to do is believe that God is real and that you will receive a salvation for sins. Somehow your past sins will be erased and somehow you will get to heaven. Many have also left out the part where you live your life for God. Many have left out the part where you need to repent and change!</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">Again, what did people see in God that they left him? Why is it that so many people refuse to believe in God? Is it because there was an unanswered prayer? Is it because someone who claimed to be Christian wronged them? Is it because their parents died? Is it because they think it&#8217;s silly because they think that others think it&#8217;s silly (peer pressure)? People begin to follow other idols such as the dream job, the ideal family, the American Dream, the next promotion, money. How does this compare with the God of the Universe? What happened to God being GOD? Then again, how does this apply to myself?</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">When I first became a Christian, I was very excited. I was all about making sure that everyone knew the truth regardless of whether or not they liked it. Now, of course, there are ways to talk to other people. In my nature, I wanted to put others down to show that I was right. And sadly, that turned away many people. I was so focused on trying to show others that I was right that I did many things that I laugh at today. And that&#8217;s not even that long ago!</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">And yet, I find myself thinking about what I did today. I did not have a very productive day. I did not have class today and I felt like I could take the day off. You know those days when we feel like not doing anything? Well, today was one of those days for me. But that means that I was not about my life&#8217;s purpose for a day. And since my life&#8217;s purpose is to try to align myself to God&#8217;s purpose, how can I say I had a good day? How can I say that I had a productive day? It&#8217;s crazy how the Scriptures can cut my heart&#8230;</p>
<p class="line" style="text-align:left;">This quiet time will have to continue through tomorrow. This is good stuff and I want to make sure that I have a thorough understanding.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/">Faithfulness, Or Lack Thereof</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/">MARALKAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/faithfulness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
