<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>excellent &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/excellent/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:09:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>excellent &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Excellent Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excellent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ILoveMyChurchICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-363"></span>Continuing on my reading of Mark, I realized one thing. Jesus loves us and therefore heals us. But not just a superficial remedy. He heals completely and thoroughly, leaving no blemish behind.</p>
<p>In Mark 7, Jesus healed a deaf and mute man. Now, being sensitive to those who are deaf and mute, this is something that, according to the hearing world, is considered a disease of some sort. But Jesus did something incredible.</p>
<blockquote><p>Then Jesus left the vicinity of Tyre and went through Sidon, down to the Sea of Galilee and into the region of the Decapolis. There some people brought to him a man who was deaf and could hardly talk, and they begged Jesus to place his hand on him.</p>
<p>After he took him aside, away from the crowd, Jesus put his fingers into the man’s ears. Then he spit and touched the man’s tongue. He looked up to heaven and with a deep sigh said to him, “Ephphatha!” (which means “Be opened!”). At this, the man’s ears were opened, his tongue was loosened and he began to speak plainly.</p>
<p>Jesus commanded them not to tell anyone. But the more he did so, the more they kept talking about it. People were overwhelmed with amazement. “He has done everything well,” they said. “He even makes the deaf hear and the mute speak.” — Mark 7:31-37 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p>Today, modern procedures for someone to hear requires Deaf people to have an intrusive device that looks obvious on them. These devices, can be very painful experiences to those who have lived deaf lives. I&#8217;ve heard many accounts of these hearing aids comparing the sudden influx of noise to a massive train wreck playing in our ears at volume levels too intense for us to bear. Deaf people with hearing aids must go through a lot in order to be part of the hearing world. Again, these hearing aids cause massive &#8220;migraine&#8221; headaches that are too much to bear.</p>
<p>But Jesus healed a man at a time when this was not even a possibility in people&#8217;s minds. Jesus installed a language into a man&#8217;s mind. He cured a man of would-be headaches and even have the man muscle memory for the tongue, that he would be able to speak possibly as if he had spoken the language his whole life. That&#8217;s amazing!</p>
<p>My major in school is cognitive science. Because of it, I&#8217;m able to appreciate the fact that this man had to receive a sudden influx of information into his brain, had to have many neural pathways changed, and he needed to have nerve paths hardened before Jesus&#8217;s fingers left the man&#8217;s ears. And that&#8217;s not even touching the fact that the man&#8217;s ears are now sensitive to sound. The cochlea, the inner ear, is now able to perceive sound the way it is supposed to. This man was also <em>probably</em> able to communicate the wonders of God and Jesus in sign language as well! This was definitely a contribution to the world evangelization described in the book of Acts. I say the word &#8220;probably&#8221; with caution; it&#8217;s not in the Bible!</p>
<p>Now, Jesus loved this man and healed him completely. I now ask myself this question&#8230; How do I love others? Do I love someone &#8220;just enough&#8221;? Or do I go out of my way to love my brothers, sisters, and those outside? I had a conversation with a fellow student regarding the Catholic faith. We differed on the basis that I hold the Bible to be the ultimate and final authority in all things related to God and my life. But he holds the Church to be the final authority and the Bible is merely a book of guidelines. We differ and I don&#8217;t hold it against him. But I do tell him to challenge his way of thinking. This is the primary way by which false doctrines came into the church. This is the main reason why so many people think they&#8217;re doing all things right. This is why people believe that they can be saved with a simple prayer. It&#8217;s because churches have subjected the Bible to be merely a book of guidelines. It&#8217;s not the Word of God. It&#8217;s instead just a set of inspired writings that have man&#8217;s intentions written all over them. He thinks that one receives salvation through the Eucharist tradition of the Catholic church.</p>
<p>Regardless of how much I know, I still will not be able to win him over using knowledge of the Scriptures. It&#8217;s loving excellently as Jesus did. It&#8217;s dying to myself and not getting into quarrels about knowledge. It&#8217;s truly living a pure life. It&#8217;s taking care of my life and my doctrine.</p>
<blockquote><p><sup>16</sup> Watch your life and doctrine closely. Persevere in them, because if you do, you will save both yourself and your hearers. — 1 Timothy 4:16</p></blockquote>
<p>And also:</p>
<blockquote><p>1 Jesus knew that the Father had put all things under his power, and that he had come from God and was returning to God; so he got up from the meal, took off his outer clothing, and wrapped a towel around his waist. After that, he poured water into a basin and began to wash his disciples’ feet, drying them with the towel that was wrapped around him.</p>
<p>He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, “Lord, are you going to wash my feet?”</p>
<p>Jesus replied, “You do not realize now what I am doing, but later you will understand.”</p>
<p>“No,” said Peter, “you shall never wash my feet.”</p>
<p>Jesus answered, “Unless I wash you, you have no part with me.”</p>
<p>“Then, Lord,” Simon Peter replied, “not just my feet but my hands and my head as well!”</p>
<p>12 When he had finished washing their feet, he put on his clothes and returned to his place. “Do you understand what I have done for you?” he asked them. “You call me ‘Teacher’ and ‘Lord,’ and rightly so, for that is what I am. Now that I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also should wash one another’s feet. I have set you an example that you should do as I have done for you. Very truly I tell you, no servant is greater than his master, nor is a messenger greater than the one who sent him. Now that you know these things, you will be blessed if you do them.” — John 13:1-9, 12-17 NIV</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Just as Jesus loved, so I should love. There are times when I don&#8217;t feel like loving my brother. But how can I love God, who I can&#8217;t see, if I can&#8217;t love my brother, who I can see? Jesus loved excellently. I will do so as well.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">-M</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/excellent-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
