<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>unconditional love &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<atom:link href="https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/tag/unconditional-love/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<description>Disciple. Professional. BOLD.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/cropped-maralkan-logo-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>unconditional love &#8211; MARALKAN</title>
	<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Unconditional Love</title>
		<link>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/</link>
					<comments>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiet Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconditional love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://maralcan.wordpress.com/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="more-189"></span>I decided to switch up my reading. Instead of reading Jeremiah, I will read the gospels. I realized late last night that I need to have more faith to be able to be strong in all situations. (Romans 10:17 NIV)</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">And a voice came from heaven: &#8220;You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased.&#8221; — Mark 1:11 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">A Christian is a follower of Jesus. Therefore, an imitator of Jesus. God was well pleased with Jesus. Therefore, as I imitate Christ, God will be pleased with me just as Jesus pleased him in his time. What&#8217;s crazy is that God has long encouraged prophets to remain steadfast and to know his heart. But this time it was different. This time, God was pleased with Jesus before he had started his ministry! Already, this distinguishes Jesus from all of the prophets.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The question here is, how do I imitate Christ? Simple, I must learn what Jesus did and taught. How do I learn that? I can&#8217;t rely on anyone to teach me. I must do it for myself. It&#8217;s my personal relationship with God.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">So then, what are the teachings of Jesus? I guess I&#8217;m going to learn more and more as I continue to read the Bible.</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;">Application for Today</h3>
<p style="text-align:left;">Today, it seems, I will have to follow the example of Christ.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Love must be sincere.</strong> Hate what is evil; cling to what is good. <strong>Be devoted to one another in love. Honor one another above yourselves.</strong> Never be lacking in zeal, but keep your spiritual fervor, serving the Lord. Be joyful in hope, patient in affliction, faithful in prayer. Share with the Lord’s people who are in need. Practice hospitality.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Bless those who persecute you; bless and do not curse. Rejoice with those who rejoice; mourn with those who mourn. Live in harmony with one another. Do not be proud, but be willing to associate with people of low position. Do not be conceited.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Do not repay anyone evil for evil. Be careful to do what is right in the eyes of everyone. <strong>If it is possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone.</strong> Do not take revenge, my dear friends, but leave room for God’s wrath, for it is written: “It is mine to avenge; I will repay,” says the Lord. On the contrary:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">“If your enemy is hungry, feed him;<br />
if he is thirsty, give him something to drink.<br />
In doing this, you will heap burning coals on his head.”<br />
Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good. — Romans 12:9-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">and</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">We love because he first loved us. Whoever claims to love God yet hates a brother or sister is a <strong>liar</strong>. For whoever does not love their brother and sister, whom they have seen, <strong>cannot love God</strong>, whom they have not seen. And <strong>he has given us this command</strong>: Anyone who loves God must also love their brother and sister. — 1 John 4:19-21 NIV</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Christ taught many times throughout his time on earth and through his apostles&#8217; writings that we must have love for one another. I can imitate Christ by having love for my brothers (<em>adelphoi</em> means brothers and sisters). How can I love my brothers? I can definitely start by changing my character. So many times, I thought that everyone else had to change because I was doing everything right. I love people, I give sacrificially, I do more things (in my opinion) than others. But that doesn&#8217;t make me righteous. When someone ignores me I get butthurt and I tend to pull away my love because I think it&#8217;s not worth it to love a person who will not appreciate my love. But Christ commands us to love as he did. He loved despite the rejection of the apostles when he was turned in to the authorities. He loved always. So I must also always love even in the face of rejection. That way, I will overcome evil with good. That way I can imitate Christ and live a life pleasing to God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://maralkan.github.io/TestWordPress/unconditional-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
